Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 19.02.13 16:47:28
-=伊甸园论坛www.ydy.com=- 荣誉出品  本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=YTET小组工作室=-  翻译:笨笨  校对:笨笨
人类真是不幸.
Woe unto man.
勇敢的阿基里斯, 接受血淋淋的死亡考验...
Brave Achilles, slain in trial by blood...
为了获得, 梅内莱厄斯的新娘.
for prize, the bride of Menelaus.
安提歌尼的父亲, 底比斯的统治者,
And father of Antigone, ruler of Thebes,
赎罪的渴望使自己盲目.
self-rendered sightless by lust for expiation.
成为受迷惑愿望的牺牲者.
Lost victim of bewildered desire.
詹森的太太也不走运.
Nor has Jason's wife fared better.
只为了复仇的愤怒而献出生命.
Giving life only to reclaim it in vengeful fury.
为了理解心灵的方式...
For to understand the ways of the heart...
清楚地领会诸神的邪恶和无能,
is to grasp as clearly the malice or ineptitude of the gods,
他们徒劳而又笨拙的努力, 想制造出完美的替代品
who, in their vain and clumsy labors to create a flawless surrogate,
只给人类留下了茫然和不完美.
have left mankind but dazed and incomplete.
看看, 例如, Lenny weinrib的情形,
Take, for instance, the case of Lenny Weinrib,
就像希腊神话和它永恒的宿命.
a tale as Greek and timeless as fate itself.
- Lenny, 我们要个孩子吧. - 嘿!
- Lenny, let's have a baby. - Hey!
孩子? 为什么? 因为她怀孕了, 你也想要个孩子?
A baby? Why? Because she's pregnant, you want to have a baby?
- 不. 这是个好主意. - 你可以培养自己的中量级选手.
- No. It's a great idea. - You could raise your own middleweight.
- 我不需要什么中量级选手. - 次轻量级选手也行.
- I don't want a middleweight. - Flyweight.
- 不, 这会很有趣. - 你有过孩子吗?
- No, it'd be fun. - Have you ever had children?
- 不, 我没有. - 为什么没有?
- No, I've never had children. - Why not?
什么意思, ''为什么没有?''  '因为我的第一个老婆不想要孩子.
What do you mean, "why not?" 'Cause my first wife didn't want to have a child.
- 而且我从来没有再婚, 所以-- - 噢, 说得真好.
- Then I never remarried really, so-- - Oh, that's great.
- 那我算什么, 善变的人? - 到目前为止是.
- What am I, chopped liver? - Until now.
- 是吗? - 我没有再婚-- 因为你没有让我离婚.
- Yeah? - I never-- You didn't let me finish.
- 不, 是你忘了. - 现在你改变想法了.你以前不想要孩子的.
- No, you'd forgotten. - Now you've changed your mind. You didn't want to have a child.
- 你们应该要个孩子. - 就像立体声音响. 给他一个机会.
- You should have kids. - It's like stereo. Give him a break.
- 你不想要孩子? - 噢, 我们--
- You don't want a kid? - Oh, we--
我们刚认识时, 她不喜欢去海滩;  她不喜欢汉普顿的人;
When we first met, she didn't like the beach; she hated the Hamptons;
她不想要孩子; 她喜欢东北部地区, 她不想搬家.
she didn't want to have kids; she loved the Upper East Side, she didn't want to move.
现在她突然说她想要孩子 想搬到Tribeca.
Now suddenly she's making noise about having a kid and moving to Tribeca.
- 除非画廊搬到市中心去. - 嗯, 怀孕的感觉好极了.
- Only if the gallery moves downtown. - Well, being pregnant is great.
- 是吗? - 我喜欢这样. 你会被照顾得像英国女王一样.
-  Yeah? - I love it. You get treated like the Queen of England.
- 当然. - 你说得好象这是个美好的事.
- Sure. - You say that like it's a good thing.
- 嗯, 我喜欢纵容孩子. - 她是喜欢.
- Well, I like the pampering. - She does like it.
- 是吗? - 是的, 感觉太棒了.
- Yeah? - Yeah, it's fantastic.
我现在没有时间.
I can't give up the time right now.
我的工作上有太多令人兴奋的事.
There are too many exciting things happening in my business.
- 让我问你一个问题. - 什么?
- So let me ask you a question. - What?
我很好奇. 如果你不怀孕 你怎么能获得成功? .
How do you plan to swing it without being pregnant? I'm curious.
- 问得好. 真是个好问题. - 不, 这很简单.
- Good question. Very good question. - No, it's easy.
- 我们可以收养. 哦, 是的. - 嗯.
- We'll adopt. Oh, well. - Mmm.
- 不包括我. 我可不想收养. - 说到问题上了.
- Not me. I don't want to adopt. -  There you go.
- 为什么不? 这是个好主意. - 不. 不行.
- Why not? That's a good idea. - No. No.
- 你傻啦. 要, 要我的基因? - 是吗?
- You must be nuts. With, with my genes? - Yeah?
- 收养? 我有获奖的基因. - 噢, 上帝.
- To adopt? I have award-winning genes. - Oh, God.
- 我要把它们遗传下去. - 不, 太疯狂了. 不, 这--
- I want to pass them on. - No, that's crazy. No, the--
我们不想租车也是因为同样的理由, 知道吗?
It's for the same reason we don't lease a car, okay?
- '因为这是所有权的自尊问题. - 好吧.
- 'Cause it's pride of ownership. - Okay.
- 我不想收养孩子. - 不. 听着, 我很抱歉, Lenny.
- And I don't want to adopt a child. - No. Look, I'm sorry, Lenny.
这太疯狂了 '这个世界上到处都是贫穷的孩子.
It's crazy 'cause the world is full of needy kids.
- 你知道, 她说得对. - 这是事实.
- You know, she's right. -  That's true.
- 我知道, 可是-- 可我-- - 不, 我就是这个意思.
- I know, but that-- You know, but I-- - No, I mean it.
为什么要使这个世界人口过剩呢 还有那么多没有父母的孩子?
Why overpopulate the world when there are thousands of parent-less kids?
就因为你不想有那种孕妇的晨吐反应, 对吗?
Just because you don't want to get morning sickness, right?
- 不, 不是这样. - 那就是你想收养孩子的理由.
- No, it's not true. - That's why you want to adopt a kid.
是因为我现在不能放弃一年的时间来做这些事.
I just can't afford to give up a year just now.
算了吧. 不说这个了. 我不想--
Forget it. Subject is closed. I don't wanna--
我担心我们可能会收养一个坏“种子”.
I'd be afraid that I might get a bad seed.
- 噢, 你有妄想症吧. - 噢, 别这样.
- Oh, you're paranoid. - Oh, come on.
真的! 什么-- 你总是从小报上读这些消息.
That's right! What-- You read that in the tabloids all the time.
- 不会. 坏“种子”. - 是的.
- No. A bad seed. - That's right.
是, 我们收养一个可爱的小男孩, 到他13岁了,
Yeah, we adopt some sweet little boy, and then he turns 13,
我们晚上睡觉的时候, 他会用斧子劈开我们的头.
we'd go to sleep at night, he'd split our head open with an axe.
听着, 你为什么要和他说这些? 你知道Lenny的想象力很丰富的.
Listen, why'd you have to go and tell him that? You know Lenny's got a vivid imagination.
- 这是很普通的事. - 我也看到过. 你想我和他说什么呢?
- It's a common occurrence. - I read the same paper. What do you want me to tell you?
无论如何, 你们说 ''他'' 是什么意思 ? 为什么我们不能收养一个女孩 ?
Anyway, what do you mean "he"? Why can't we adopt a girl?
- 我们什么也不收养.不管男孩还是女孩. - 一个小女孩.
- We're not adopting anything. I want no sex. - A little girl.
让男人打游击或者点防守, 好吗?
Let the guy have a short stop or a point guard, will ya?
我们可以买单了吗? 我们-- 我们可以离开这里了吗?
Can we get a check? Can we-- Can we please get out of here?
我来买单. 今晚我付帐.
I'll take the check. I'm paying tonight.
- 是. - 你? 我没听错吧.
- Yes. - You? I'm stunned.
你付钱, 你打破纪录了. 你-- 再来一次 你就打破DiMaggio的纪录-- 56次连续.
You pay, you break your record. You-- One more and you break DiMaggio's record-- 56 straight.
这不是真的. 喂, 客气点.
That's not true. Now, be nice.
拉伊俄斯, 伟大的父亲, 请讲.
Laius, proud father, speak.
我很开心有一个孩子...
I, with joy, did have a son...
这么漂亮, 这么聪明，又这么勇敢
so fair, so clearheaded and brave,
因为他的到来我有无限的快乐.
that I a thousand pleasures did derive from his presence.
然后发生了什么事?
So what happens?
有一天他杀了我.
One day he kills me.
你不会相信, 他逃跑了, 还霸占了我的妻子.
And don't you think, he runs off and marries my wife.
可怜的俄狄浦斯, 底比斯的国王.
Poor Oedipus, king of Thebes.
我的儿子, 我的儿子 无情地杀死了...
My son, my son did slay unwittingly...
我高贵的丈夫...
my noble husband...
然后, 他根本没有意识到, 他是在催促我,
and did, without realizing, hasten with me,
他亲爱的母亲, 和他上床
his loving mother, to lustful bed.
一个淫乱的行业因此产生...
And a whole profession was born...
有时1个小时收取200美元,
charging sometimes 200 an hour,
而且还是以50分钟为1个小时.
and a 50-minute hour at that.
那么为什么现在孩子是一个主要话题?
And why a child now, out of left field?
人们希望它不是用来填补婚姻成长的空虚.
One hopes it's not to fill some growing void in their marriage.
让她去吧.
Leave her be.
一个女人想成为母亲的愿望和地球一样古老.
A woman's urge to motherhood is old as the earth.
孩子们长大了; 搬出去了.
Children grow up; they move out.
搬到辛辛纳提那样荒唐的地方...
Sometimes to ridiculous places like Cincinnati...
也许有时候搬到爱达荷州的博伊西.
or Boise, Idaho.
然后你再也见不到他们.
Then you never see them again.
你会认为偶尔他们会拿起电话.
You'd think once in a while they'd pick up a phone.
但是weinrib的婚姻里有成长的空虚吗?
But is there a growing void in the Weinrib's marriage?
我们并没有说它有.
We didn't say there was.
我们只是猜测所有的可能性.
We're all just speculating on possible motives.
孩子是一个严肃的话题.
Children are serious stuff.
看, 这儿有个人杀了他父亲...
Look, here's a man who killed his father...
而且和他母亲上床.
and slept with his mother.
我不愿意告诉你 哈莱姆区的人怎么叫我的儿子.
I hate to tell you what they call my son in Harlem.
你好.
Hello.
- 我们可以收养一个孩子了. - 你说真的吗?
- There's a baby we can adopt. - Are you serious?
我和Carolyn Hester谈过 她为我们找到了个孩子.
I spoke to Carolyn Hester and she's found an infant for us.
- 不过我们要快点决定. - 我不想要孩子.
- But we have to act quickly. - I don't want a kid.
好了, Lenny, 你知道这有多难得吗.
Well, Lenny, you know how hard it is.
听着, 这个孩子今天刚出生, 完全健康.
And look, the baby's one day old, totally healthy.
是未婚妈妈, 没有病.
Unwed mother, no diseases.
而且是个男孩. 你不是想要个男孩吗.
And it's a boy. You wanted a boy.
Amanda, 我现在不能和你谈这个.
Amanda, I can't get into this with you now.
这里不是讨论这个的地方.
This is not the place to have this discussion.
我让Carolyn帮我们留意. 她在收养方面很有经验.
I told Carolyn to be on the lookout. She's experienced with adoptions.
她知道该注意什么. 这是个男孩, 健康, 早上出生的.
She knows what she's doing. It's a boy, healthy, born this morning.
没有附带条件, 如果我们快点决定.
No strings, if we act quickly.
Le-- 听着, 我-- 我决定了.
Le-- Look, I-- I gotta put my foot down.
如-如-- 如果你想谈这个, 我们可以再找个时间.
I-I-- If you want to discuss this another time, we can.
可是如果你要我马上回答, 肯定 ''不行.''
But if you gotta have a fast answer, it's definitely "no."
- 嗨! 嗨.
- Hi! Hi.
- 抱着他的头? - 他真可爱.
- You got his head? - He's adorable.
- 是啊. 噢, 上帝.
- Yes. Oh, God.
太棒了. 你知道吗,  这孩子永远不会成为拳击手.
This is great. This kid is never going to be a fighter, you know.
我要赶快给他补充一些重量 你看他真的轻得像根羽毛.
I gotta run out and get some weights because he's really light as a feather.
- 是啊, 我想应该让我来抱一会儿. - 嗨.
- Yeah, perhaps I should have him back. - Hi.
是啊. 他在哭了, 还是你来抱他吧.
Yeah. Maybe you better hold him 'cause he's crying.
- 对, 对, 对. - 他哭了.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - He's crying.
- 好. 好. 没事的. 没事.
- Okay. Okay. It's okay. It's okay.
- 真是个好孩子. - 这太棒了.
- That's a good boy. - That's so great.
如果我手上有什么好东西, 都让它传到你身上去.
If there's any greatness in my hands, let it pass into your body.
- 抱好了. - 这孩子将会是一个很棒的小孩!
- Get a grip on yourself. - This kid is gonna be a great kid!
- 噢, 是的. - 他太棒了!
- Oh, yeah. - He's fabulous!
- 你好了吧. - 你想叫他什么呢?
- You're okay now. - What do you wanna call him?
- 噢, 太难以置信了. 是啊. - 叫他?
- Oh, this is unbelievable. Yeah. - Call him?
- 噢, Eric怎么样 ? - Eric ? 这孩子又不是海盗.
- Oh, wh-- what about Eric? - Eric? The kid's not a Viking.
你知道吗, 我想用我 心目中的英雄的名字给他取名.
I wanna call him, name him, you know, for one of my heroes.
- 就像? - 我不知道. Groucho怎么样 ?
- Like what? - I don't know. What about Groucho?
- Groucho ? 哦, 现实一点. - 不, 我是认真的.
- Groucho? Oh, get real. - No, I'm serious.
这是个好名字-- 你知道吗. 我-- 我不知道. 你看--
It's a great-- You know. I-- I don't know. What--
Phineas怎么样 ? 你喜欢Phineas这个名字吗 ?
What about Phineas? Do you like Phineas?
Phineas ? 你在开玩笑吗 ?
Phineas? Are you joking?
Phineas是那个取消抵押品赎回权的家伙.
Phineas is the guy who forecloses on the mortgage.
我不想把他叫做Phineas.  他这么可爱.
I don't want to call this kid Phineas. He's adorable.
- 太妙了. 你看-- 看, 嗯-- 让我想想. - 嗯.
- That's so great. What-- What, uh-- Let me think. - Well.
- Django怎么样 ? - Django ?
- What about Django? - Django?
Django, 对. 就像Django Reinhardt, 那个一流的吉他手.
Django, yeah. After Django Reinhardt, the great guitar player.
- Django weinrib ? - 这是对weinrib名字的侮辱.
- Django Weinrib? - That's the curse of the Weinrib name.
- 和什么都不合适. weinrib这个姓配什么都不合适. - 哦, 好吧, 好吧.
- It doesn't go with anything. Nothing goes with Weinrib. - Well, okay, okay.
简单一点的像Ben, 你觉得怎么样 ?
What about something simple like, you know, Ben?
- 你想把他叫做Ben weinrib ? - 对啊.
- You want to call him Ben Weinrib? - Yeah.
什么, 他会成为拉米牌冠军?
What, he's gonna be a-a-a gin rummy champion?
- 我的意思是. - 对, 嗯, 你想否认你的遗传? 嗯?
- I mean, you know. - Yeah, well, you want to deny your heritage? Huh?
你知道, 我-我只是想给他取一个好名字.
Well, you know, I-I just want the kid to have a great name.
- 好吧. - Sugar Ray weinrib怎么样 ?
- Yeah. - What about Sugar Ray Weinrib?
Holden, 就像Holden Caulfield.
Holden, after Holden Caulfield.
你看, 如果我们用你的姓的话,  Holden这个名字就可以.
You see, Holden is one of those things that works if we use your maiden name.
- 如果是Holden Sloane, 而不是Holden weinrib. - 对.
- If it's Holden Sloane, but not Holden Weinrib. - Yeah.
这孩子太可爱了!
The kid is so cute!
我不信他-- Cole怎么样 ?
I can't believe he's-- What about Cole?
- Cole ? - Cole weinrib. Harpo weinrib.
- Cole? - Cole Weinrib. Harpo Weinrib.
- Harpo ? 不行. - Earl the Pearl weinrib怎么样 ?
- Harpo? No. - How about Earl the Pearl Weinrib?
- 这个太完美了. - 噢, 天哪! 不行.
- That would be so perfect. - Oh, God! No.
- 好吧, 那-- 那Shane怎么样 ? 你喜欢Shane这个名字吗 ? - 不错.
- Okay, what-- what about Shane? You like the name Shane? - Yeah.
- Shane挺好的. - Shane应该可以.
- Shane's pretty. - Shane would be okay.
不过换过来说, 你可不想一个 高级法院的法官叫做Shane.
On the other hand, you wouldn't want a Supreme Court Justice called Shane.
噢, 他妈的. 我知道了. 有了.
Oh, Jesus. I got it. I got it.
太妙了. 这个太妙了.
Brilliant. This is so brilliant.
- 有了? 有准备了吗 ? 你准备好了吗? - 嗯.
- Got it? Ready? Are you ready? - Mm-hmm.
- Thelonius weinrib. - Max ! Max怎么样 ?
- Thelonius Weinrib. - Max! What about Max?
- Max ? - 对, Max.
- Max? - Yeah, Max.
Max. 噢, 看他多可爱.
Max. Oh, look how cute he is.
- 我想抱抱他. Max可以. - 他太可爱了. 他笑了.
- I wanna hold him. Max is okay. - He's so sweet. He's smiling.
- Max weinrib医生. 我喜欢Max这个名字. - 是啊, Max很好.
- Dr. Max Weinrib. I like the name Max. - Yeah, Max is good.
- 又简单. - 议员Max weinrib不错吧 ?
- It's simple. - How about Senator Max Weinrib?
- 看他的小舌头. - Rabbi Max-- Rabbi Max weinrib ?
- Little tongue. - Rabbi Max-- Rabbi Max Weinrib?
不. 我想我们应该再仔细考虑一下Max.
No. Maybe we should rethink Max for a minute.
- 噢, 他太棒了. - 他很开心. 我想他喜欢我们.
- Oh, he's so great. - He's happy. I think he likes us.
- 他看起来像你. - 像我?
- He looks like you. - He looks like me?
对啊.
Yeah.
他看起来更像Broderick Crawford一点.
He looks like Broderick Crawford a little bit.
- 他真聪明. - 对啊.
- He's so smart. - Yeah.
他对事物慢慢开始熟悉了.
He picks up on everything.
他性格很好. 知道吗, 你把他叫醒后, 他一直在笑, 很快乐.
He's got a great personality. You know, you wake him up, he's always smiling and upbeat.
- 像我. - 当你小的时候你也这样.
- Like me. - You were like that when you were a baby.
- 对, 他很会说话. - 是啊, 他身边有一个作家...
- Yeah, he's so verbal. - Well, he's around a writer...
和一个艺术家, 对吧 ?
and an art expert, right?
听着, 你什么时候把画廊搬到市中心区?
Listen, when are you going to move the gallery downtown?
好了, 妈妈, 我们不愿意 谈论这个问题 '因为, 你知道,
Yeah, Mother, we don't want to get into that discussion 'cause, you know,
我觉得我们应该搬， 可是Lenny是个执著的东北区人.
I think we should move and Lenny is a devoted Upper East-sider.
或者说他反对任何形式的变化?
Or shall I say is opposed to change in any form?
- 我不知道. - 太难以置信了.
-  I don't know. - It's unbelievable.
这孩子太难以置信了. 我给他买了个火车,  他自己把它拼好了.
The kid is unbelievable. I got him trains, he put 'em together himself.
火车 ? 我以为你买的是建筑拼装玩具.
Trains? I thought you bought him an Erector Set.
我是给他买了建筑拼装玩具. 而且-- 而且我还给他买了个三轮车.
I got him an Erector Set, yeah. And-- And I also got him this tricycle.
- 等等. 还有这套塑料厨房玩具? - Max, 我给你买了三轮车.
- Wait. And the whole plastic kitchen? - Max, I got you a tricycle.
Lenny, 你不能给他买这么多玩具.
Lenny, you can't buy him so much.
- Max, 我给你买了三轮车. - 你看看!
- Max, I got you a tricycle. - Look at that!
- 你不能给他买这么多玩具.
- You can't buy him so much stuff.
- 不, 不. 我还给他买了溜冰鞋. - 溜冰鞋?
- No, no. I also got him skates. - Skates?
对. 我还买了一些东西还没送来.
Yeah. And I got a couple more things on the way in, you know.
一辆小卡车会把它们送到门口.
A small truck is gonna pull up in front of the house.
- 那你明年还想给他买什么? - 有没有人想喝点什么?
- What are you gonna get next year? - Does anyone want anything to drink?
- 往前. 投篮.
- Go ahead. Shoot.
再来一次.
Try again.
你没想过长大要干什么吗, Max ?
You ever think about what you want to be when you grow up, Max?
嗯, 我不知道. 也许做一个室内设计师.
Hmm, I don't know. Maybe an interior decorator.
- 什么? - 开玩笑, 开玩笑.
- What? - Just kidding, just kidding.
嗯, 别开玩笑. 这儿. 来.
Well, don't kid. Here. Come on.
好的, 这些放到卧室去. 跟我来.
Okay, those go in the bedroom. Okay, you follow me.
- 帮我一下. - 为什么我们要搬家?
- Give me a hand with this. - Why did we move?
什么意思, ''为什么我们要搬家?'' 我来告诉你.
What do you mean, "Why did we move?" I told you.
我们搬家 '因为-- '因为, '因为你妈妈想搬.
We moved 'cause-- 'cause, you know, 'cause your mother wanted to move.
'因为, 你知道, 你妈妈工作的 那个画廊搬到市中心去了...
'Cause, you know, the art gallery she works at has moved downtown...
而且, 她也想搬.
and, you know, she wanted to move.
- 你的足球在这儿. - 你和妈妈之间谁是老板?
- Here's your football. - Who's the boss between you and Mommy?
- 什么问题? - 你和妈妈之间谁是老板?
- What is the question? - Who's the boss between you and Mommy?
谁是老板? 这还用问吗?
Who is the boss? You have to ask that?
- 你不知道我和你妈妈谁是老板? - 不知道.
- You don't know who the boss is between me and Mommy? - No.
我是老板, 知道吗? 你妈妈-- 你妈妈只是做决定的人.
I'm the boss, okay? Mommy-- Mommy's only the decision maker.
你知道吗, 区别就是, 嗯--
You know, there's a difference between, uh--
你妈妈-- 你妈妈告诉我们该做什么
You know, Mommy-- Mommy says what we do and, and, uh,
我可以决定怎么去做.
I have control of the channel changer.
- 给你-- 你的蜡笔在这儿. - 谢谢.
- Here-- Here's your crayons. - Thanks.
我们刚搬到附近 我们希望Max可以上最好的学校.
We're new in the neighborhood and we want Max to be really in the best school.
- 哦, 这儿就是. - 是 '因为他是个非常, 非常聪明的孩子.
- Oh, but this is it. - It's 'cause he's a very, very bright kid.
- 我的意思是, 真的很聪明. - 对, 他真的很棒.
- I mean, really bright. - Yeah, he's really great.
是, 我知道. 我看过他的测试成绩 确实很好.
Yes, I know. I saw his test scores and they're wonderful.
- 真的很好. - 我知道. 他还很有幽默感.
- They are. Yeah. - I know. And he's got a great sense of humor.
- 他是个可爱的孩子. 他真的很可爱. - 他性格很好.
- He's a sweet kid. He's a really sweet kid. - He's got a great personality.
太好了. 嗯, 我想和你谈谈 有关我们的一些特殊安排...
Wonderful. Well, I wanted to talk to you about a special program...
对那些聪明学生的特殊安排.
that we have for bright students.
- 真的吗 ? 他合格吗?
- Really? And he qualifies?
- 哦, 对. 完全合格. - 不好意思. 我接个电话.
- Oh, yes. Absolutely. - Sorry. Excuse me.
- 没问题. - 因为-- 当你听到他的语法,
- Certainly. - Because-- when you hear his syntax,
- 喂 ? 哦, 嗨. - 太了不起了.
- Hello? Oh, hi. - it's amazing.
- 语言能力测试显示... - 他的词汇很好, 嗯, 他的语法--
- Verbal skills are telling. - His vocabulary is good, but his syntax is--
- 哦, 很棒. - 他说话象个大人.
- Oh, great. - He speaks like a grown-up.
- 不好意思. Lenny ? - 我们能做的就是--
- Sorry. Lenny? - What we can do is--
- 不好意思. 等一下. - 哦, 当然.
- Sorry. Excuse me. - Oh, certainly.
我们今晚能不能去圆形剧场 和多里安夫妇吃饭?
Can we meet the Dorians tonight for dinner at Le Cirque?
多里安夫妇? 不行. 因为我们 要去看Edward Albee的演出.
The Dorians? No. Because we have tickets to the Edward Albee play.
- 听着, 我不能去. - 我们一定要去. 我们已经等了这么久了.
- Listen, I can't. - We have to. We've been waiting for so long.
你不一定要去, 但我真的要去.
You don't have to go, but I really should go.
我, 嗯-- 不行.
I, uh-- No.
- 这已经是这个星期我们第二次取消去哪里了. - 和Bud一起去吧.
- This will be the second time this week we cancelled something. - Go with Bud.
- 哦, 好吧. - 我不想和Bud一起去. 我又不是娶了Bud.
- Oh, okay. - I don't want to go with Bud. I'm not married to Bud.
听着, 去吧. 我们现在可以不谈这个吗?
Listen, go. Can we not discuss it now?
哦, 天哪! 太尴尬了.
Oh, my God! That was embarrassing.
什么, 就因为我又不想 和世界上最无趣的一对夫妇吃饭.
Well, just because I don't want to have dinner yet again with the world's dullest couple.
对啊, 总有一天他们会 赞助我自己的画廊.
Yeah, well, someday they may sponsor me for my own gallery.
- 我说了我去. 我和你一起去. - 真的吗?
- I said I'd go. I'm going with you. - Yeah?
可是我们有演出的票. 太可惜了.
But we got tickets to a show. It's a shame.
这次尽量加入我们 别整个晚上像僵尸一样坐在那里.
This time try and join in and don't sit there like some zombie all night.
嘿, 上次我加入你们了, 可你却发火了.
Hey, last time I joined in, you got angry with me.
对啊, '因为我们在谈论I.M.Pei博物馆,  不是Muhammad Ali.
Yeah, 'cause we were discussing the l.M. Pei Museum, not Muhammad Ali.
好吧, 是我离题了. 我跟不上那些话题.
Well, my mind wandered. I can't keep on those topics.
我只是不想永远都做 Bender画廊的“马达动力”.
I just don't want to be the motor power of the Bender Gallery forever.
我想要自己的Amanda Sloane画廊.
I want the Amanda Sloane Gallery.
不是Amanda weinrib, '因为这会有发音问题的.
Not Amanda Weinrib, 'cause there's a euphony problem.
Three, four, run. Three, four, and break the ball.
-  Play 88! - I hope they don't play like this.
- 88! Ten-hut!
怎么了? 你看起来很沮丧.
What's the matter? You seem down.
- 没什么, 我很好. - 你很好?
- No, I'm fine. - You're fine?
你肯定在想什么, Lenny.
Something's on your mind, Lenny.
听着, 昨晚我又去了那种晚餐聚会.
Listen, last night I was at one of those dinner parties again.
Amanda-- 你知道, 她上星期带我去了,
Amanda-- You know, last week she took me to,
去圆形剧场和Dorians夫妇吃饭.
to Le Cirque with the Dorians.
然后昨晚又和Grossbards在派克大街吃饭.
And then last night it was with the Grossbards on Park Avenue.
之后, 我们开车回家...
And then after that, we were driving home...
我不知道该说什么.
and I don't know what to say.
那是星期六晚上, 我们停在 派克大街前的红灯前.
It was Saturday night, you know, and we stopped for a light over on Park Avenue.
我看到车窗外一个男人和一个漂亮的女生.
I looked out the window and I see some guy and this pretty girl.
他们正散步回家,
And, you know, they're walking home and, you know,
那个男的手里拿着星期日日报.
the guy's carrying the Sunday papers.
看起来他们在一起很开心, 你知道吗.
It looked like they were having so much fun, you know.
而且, 你知道-- 我不知道, 我--
And, you know-- I don't know, I--
我记得以前我和Amanda在一起感觉很棒...
I remember how great it used to be with me and Amanda...
在以前的公寓里, 你知道, 感觉非常浪漫.
in our first apartment, you know, how romantic it was.
在那些日子里, 我们一起散步逛街...
You know, in those days it was just a kick shopping together...
或者, 只是走在纽约街头.
or, you know, just walking the New York streets, you know.
然而Max来了以后, 所有事情都这么美好.
Then when Max came, everything was so great, you know.
我们曾有这么美妙的时光.
We had such terrific times.
我不知道, 已经很久没有这种感觉了, 我们之间曾经的激情.
I don't know, it's been so long since there's been, you know, the old passion between us.
我不知道, 可这是我第一次有这样的想法.
I don't know, but it was the first time I had any of those thoughts.
而且, 这让我感到很不安.
And, you know, they made me feel nervous.
你今晚不太高兴.
You weren't too pleasant this evening.
为什么, '因为我说不去 你老板Jerry Bender...
Why, 'cause I said no about going to your boss Jerry Bender's house...
- 在汉普顿的家? - 我没事.
- in the Hamptons? - I'll be fine.
我不喜欢汉普顿的人. 你知道的, 就像你自己以前也不喜欢海滩.
I don't like the Hamptons. You know, you used to hate the beach yourself.
对, 但是不包括他的生活方式. lt's private and beautiful.
Yeah, not the way he lives. It's private and beautiful.
你到底为什么发火 ?
What are you getting so angry about?
- '因为你不想去. - 上次我们去了, 结果我喝得烂醉.
- 'Cause you won't come. - Last time we went, I got a tick.
- 喝醉 ? 哦, 噢. 有什么大不了的. - 对你来说, 是没什么大不了的.
- A tick? Oh, wow. Big deal. - For you, it wasn't a big deal.
- 可是我把裤子脱了, 我两腿间有一个黑东西. - 所有人都会去.
- But I took my pants off, I had a black thing living in my leg. - Everyone will be there.
为了那些潜在的关系, 我可以忍受醉几次.
For the potential contacts, I can put up with a few ticks.
我不能-- 什么关系 ?
I don't-- What contacts?
你知道吗, 听起来你像一个国际间谍.
You know, it's like you're an international spy.
- 你的关系遍布全城. - 我只想要一个自己的画廊, 很快就会有了.
- You got contacts all over town. - I plan to have my own gallery, and soon.
太不可思议了, 这些年你变了好多.
You've changed unbelievably over the years.
- 哦, 是吗 ? 你知道什么啊, Lenny ? - 你过去不喜欢这些.
- Oh, yeah? You know what, Lenny? - You used to hate that.
- 人会成长. 他们那些人也会成长. - 这不是成长.
- People grow. They grow. Some people. - It's not growth.
你以前不喜欢海滩. 而且Jerry Bender非常迷恋你.
You used to hate the beach. And Jerry Bender has got a crush on you.
什么?
What?
- 那个家伙一直盯着你. - 噢, 不. 简直胡说八道.
- This guy stares at you. - Oh, no. That's nuts.
- 这太疯狂了. - 他用意识羞辱了你.
- That's seriously crazy. - He mentally undresses you.
- 他只是很平常地看我. - 一定也不平常.
- That's his normal look. - It's not his normal look.
- 如果他那样看我, 我会用砖头敲他. - 好了. 好了, 我们--
- If he looked at me that way I'd hit him with a brick. - Okay. Okay, let's--
- 或者也许会亲他的嘴. - 我们不讨论这个了. 好吗 ?
- Or kiss him on the lips, maybe. - Let's drop this. Please?
你什么意思, 你找不到地方?
Well, what do you mean, you couldn't find it?
嗯, 我很抱歉. 你知道, 这里头很黑...
Well, I'm sorry. You know, it's dark in here...
而且我-- 你知道, 我们有一段时间没有那个了.
and I-- you know, we haven't done it in a while.
- 而且你刚才对我发火了. - 我没有发火.
- And then you got so angry at me. - I wasn't angry.
我没有发火. 你到处摸索 弄得我都没有兴趣了.
I wasn't angry. You were fumbling and I was getting out of the mood.
不好意思, 我找不到地方. 这-- 我们有一段时间没有那个了.
Sorry, I couldn't find it. This-- We haven't been doing it in a while.
- 好了, 不要在这儿讨论这些了. - 我没有方向感了.
- Okay, let's not get into a whole discussion here. - I lost my sense of direction.
我累了.
I'm tired.
所有的婚姻都会经历高峰和低谷期.
Every marriage goes through valleys and peaks.
- 现在只是低谷期. - 我不在意经历低谷期.
- This is like a valley. - I don't mind going through a valley.
- 可是我不想沉到海平面以下. - Lenny, 为什么要捣乱 ?
- But I don't want to sink beneath sea level here. - Lenny, why rock the boat?
你有一个聪明美丽的太太. 还有一个你所渴望的孩子.
You got a bright, beautiful wife. You got a kid that you're crazy for.
我不想捣乱. 我和你说过Max吗 ?
I'm not gonna rock the boat. Did I tell you about Max?
因为他的智商很高 他们想把他安排到特别班里.
They want to put him in a special class because he's got a high IQ.
是啊, 有这么聪明的父母. 我的意思是, 你还期望什么呢?
Yeah, well, two bright parents. I mean, what do you expect?
对, 不管他们是谁. 我的意思是, 我还是不知道.
Yeah, whoever they are. I mean, I still don't know.
这就像不断提高的优良品种.
It's like raising thoroughbreds.
这孩子肯定来自很优秀的父母.
This kid must come from good stock.
他很漂亮; 智商又很高; 他的性格很讨人喜欢.
He's good-looking; he's got a high IQ; he's got a great personality.
而且他还很幽默.
And he's amusing.
这不是我的功劳. Amanda决定所有收养的事.
This is not my doing. Amanda did the whole adoption.
我只是反对. 抱怨, 像一个傻瓜.
I just resisted. I complained, like a jerk.
我的意思是, 一个好父亲, 一个出色的母亲 才能生出像Max一样的孩子.
I mean, a good father, a dynamite mother produces a kid like Max.
你知道吗, 我觉得那个父亲 '' 死 '' 了.
I think the father's dead, you know.
- 母亲?
- The mother?
别再查下去了!
Don't go any further!
我知道你想什么, Lenny, 忘了它吧.
I know what you're thinking, Lenny, and forget it.
我怎么能忘了它? 这个想法已经埋到脑子里了.
How can I forget it? The thought's been put into my head.
哦, 该死的天意.  有些想法最好不要被想到.
Oh, cursed fate. Certain thoughts are better left unthunk.
我敢打赌这个孩子有一个很出色的母亲.
I'll bet this kid has a dynamite mother.
你凭什么认为他不是 从他父亲那里继承所有这些?
What makes you think he didn't inherit everything from his father?
所有这些 ? 这不太可能. 不管怎么样我要查明真相.
Everything? That's very unlikely. But I'm gonna find out.
让睡着的狗躺下吧.
Let sleeping dogs lie.
- 我敢打赌她很棒. - 好奇心. 就是好奇心害死了我们.
- I'll bet she's great. - Curiosity. That's what kills us.
臭氧层里并不是怪人或者废话. 而是我们的心灵和精神.
Not muggers or all that bullshit about the ozone layer. It's our own hearts and minds.
- 我要查明真相. - Lenny, 别傻了.
- I'm gonna find out. - Please, Lenny, don't be a schmuck.
我对收养的事记不太清了 因为我和Amanda很熟.
I remember the adoption vaguely because I'm somewhat friendly with Amanda.
可是我们-- 我们收养他 这还没多久呢.
But it was not that long ago that we-- that we did it.
我想起来我帮她尽量加快事情的程序.
I recall trying to expedite matters for her.
我多多少少记得 那个孩子有个单亲妈妈.
I somehow think it was a single parent with no father.
对. 就是. 这样-怎么-- 能不能知道她的名字--
Right. Exactly. So-So how-- Is it possible for me to get the name--
如果可以, 我想知道她的名字.
I'd like the name of the mother, if I could.
我们会永远保留她的档案.
That remains forever in our files.
但是就算我有, 我也不能告诉你.  我可以问一下, 你为什么想知道呢?
Even if I have it, I can't give it to you. May I ask why you want to know?
是, '因为我-我-- 我很好奇...
Yes, 'cause I-I-- I'm curious about it...
如果可以，我想了解所有的资料.
and I'm trying to get all the information that I can.
- 所以-- - 不好意思. 我只能帮到这里.
- So, so-- - I'm sorry. That's all I can help you with.
有没有可能, 嗯--
There's no possibility of, uh--
- 不行, 我们有规矩. - 我不明白. 我现在是孩子的父亲.
- No, those are the rules. - I don't understand. I'm the father of the child.
- 我不能查出谁是-- - 规矩很严格. 我们从来没有这么做过.
- I can't find out who-- - They're very firm. It's never done.
- 嗯. - 那个小孩现在怎么样 ?
- Mm-hmm. - How is the little boy doing?
- 很好. 他很聪明. 太妙了. - 是吗 ?
- Good. He's great. He's fabulous. - Yes?
- 是的. - 向Amanda问好.
- Yes. - Say hello to Amanda.
- 我能不能-- - 很抱歉.
- There's no possibility that I could-- - I'm sorry.
- 我-- - 真的很抱歉. 绝对不行.
- There's-- - Really sorry. No way.
- 好吧, 谢谢. 谢谢. - 再见.
- Okay, thank you. Thank you. - Bye-bye.
你在干什么, weinrib ?
What are you doing, Weinrib?
别烦我 ! 她马上就回来了.
Don't confuse me! She's coming back in a minute.
- 你这么做是犯法的. - 犯法 ? 还有更高的法律呢.
- You are breaking the law. - Breaking the law? There's a higher law.
我查不出谁是我孩子的母亲.
I can find out who my son's mother is.
法官不会这么看的.
The judge won't see it that way.
帮我看着点, 可以吗,  看在耶稣的份上?
Keep a lookout for me, will you, for Christ's sake?
- 我? 我是合唱队的领唱. - 那又怎么样? 看着点.
- Me? I'm the leader of the Chorus. - So what? Look out.
让你的朋友Bud帮帮你.
Get your friend Bud to help you.
Bud帮不了我. 你知道, Ellie和Amanda是好朋友.
Bud can't help me. You know, Ellie and Amanda are friendly.
- Bud守不住秘密. - 为什么这是秘密? 为什么不能让Amamda知道?
- Bud can't keep a secret. - Why is it a secret? Why can't Amanda know?
我和你争这个干嘛 ? Amanda--
What kind of argument am I getting into with you? Amanda--
'因为她不会明白的.
'Cause she wouldn't understand.
哦, 你觉得心虚 因为你已经对你孩子的母亲...
Oh, you're guilty because you already have exaggerated notions...
有过分的念头.
about your son's mother.
这可以理解 因为事情到了Amanda那里就不顺利了.
It's understandable because things are not going smoothly with Amanda.
这就是为什么你一直 只是一个合唱团的成员.
That's why you will always be a chorus member.
因为你什么也不做. 我行动了.
Because you don't do anything. I act.
我采取行动了. 我让事情发生.
I take action. I make things happen.
好吧, 他妈的快点. 我听见脚步声了.
Well, hurry the hell up. I hear footsteps.
我-我忘了我的-- 我把我的 褐色信封丢在这儿了. 我没注意到.
I-I forgot my-- I dropped my manila envelope. I didn't realize it.
- 哦. - 里头有个很重要的面谈.
- Oh. - It has an important interview in it.
和-- 和Roberto Duran的面谈.
With-- With Roberto Duran.
你想不到的, 他要去宾夕法尼亚州了.
You won't believe this, but he's heading for Pennsylvania.
人类所有的弱点里,
Of all the human weaknesses,
- 成见是最危险的. - 也是最愚蠢的.
- obsession is the most dangerous. -  And the silliest.
- 是吗 ? - 我找这里以前的一个房客,
- Yeah? - I'm looking for a former tenant here,
- 嗯-嗯 她叫Leslie wright. - 你是谁 ?
- a-a-a Leslie Wright. - Who are you?
我是她的朋友,  我相信她在这里住过--
I'm a friend of hers, and I believe she lived here at one time--
一个叫Leslie wright的 ?
a Leslie Wright?
哦, 对, 对. 我想起来 以前有一个女孩住在这里.
Oh, yeah, yeah. I remember the girl who used to live here.
- 你记得吗. 楼上那个漂亮的女孩. - 哦, 是, 对.
- You remember. The pretty one upstairs. - Yeah, yeah, right.
她只在这里住了一段时间. 你是谁 ?
She was only here for a while. Who are you?
嗯, 我是她的老朋友 我只是想找到她.
Uh, I'm just an old friend of hers and I was trying to track her down.
你知道-- 你知道 哪里可以找到她 ?
Do you know-- Do you know where I could find her?
她的名字是Leslie wailes, 不是Leslie wright. Leslie wailes.
Leslie Wailes was her name, not Leslie Wright. Leslie Wailes.
- Leslie wailes ? - wailes.
- Leslie Wailes? - Wailes.
- 她搬到纽约去了. - 你确定吗? '因为我记得她叫Leslie wright.
- She moved to New York. - You sure? 'Cause I have Leslie Wright.
Leslie-- Leslie-- 她结婚了没有, 还是--
Leslie-- Leslie-- Did she get married or--
我不知道.
I don't know.
你没有其他消息了吗 ? 你不知道哪里能找到她或是什么 ?
You have no other information? You don't know where I could find her or anything?
不知道. 我告诉过你,  她只在这里住了一段时间.
No. She was only here for a little while. I told you.
这样吧, 我把我的电话号码给你.
Look, let me give you my phone number.
如果有什么消息, 我很希望能找到她.
If anything turns up, I would love to locate her.
- 给你. 把这个给我. 我拿着这个. - 谢谢.
- Here. Give me that. I'll take that. - Thank you.
- 好的. 这样. - 不客气.
- Yeah. Okay. - You're welcome.
Lamont先生给你打电话 说他是从宾夕法尼亚打来的.
You have a phone call. Mr. Lamont. Says he's from Philadelphia.
- 哦. - 你给了他你的电话号码 ?
- Oh. - You gave him your number?
- 嗯. - 是Lenny weinrib吗 ?
- Mm-hmm. -  Is this Lenny Weinrib?
- 我是, 什么事. - 你好.
- Go ahead, sir. - Hello.
嗯, 我是Bill Lamont. 嗯, 你想找的那个女人--
Yeah, this is Bill Lamont. Um, that woman you were looking for--
我们问了另一个人, 他说她的名字叫Leslie St. James.
We asked another guy who said her name was Leslie St. James.
还说她搬到纽约去了, 现在是个演员.
Said she moved to New York City, talked about becoming an actress.
- Leslie St. James ? - 是的, 对.
- Leslie St. James? - Yes, sir. Yeah.
他记得很清楚. Leslie St. James是她用的名字.
He remembered her quite well. Leslie St. James is the name she took.
有一个叫Leslie St. James的,  她是影视临时演员协会的会员.
There was a Leslie St. James who was a member of the Screen Extras Guild.
- 对，就是这样. - 你想和我说什么 ?
- So that's that. - So what are you telling me?
那-- 那她是电影或是舞台的临时演员 ?
That-- That she was a movie extra or stage extra?
对. 我就知道这些.
Yeah. That's all I have.
嗯-- 这儿有个地址, 可是, 嗯, 你知道,
So-- And there's an address, but, uh, you know,
这本书是几年前的. 所以.
this book's a few years old. So.
我在找一个-- 她是--
I'm looking for a-- it's-- she--
叫Leslie St. James的人 或者她叫Leslie wailes.
A Leslie St. James or maybe it's a Leslie Wailes.
- 我不知道, 但是她以前住在这里. - 哦, 对, 没错. 我记得.
- I don't know, but I think she lived here. - Oh, yeah, sure. I remember.
是个高个子女孩. 她改了名字, 叫Linda Ash.
She was a tall girl. She changed her name to Linda Ash.
Linda Ash ?
Linda Ash?
对, 是个假名字. 她-- 她是拍色情片的.
Yeah, it was a fake name. She-- She did sex movies.
- 色情片 ? - 对, 你知道, 就像, 嗯, '' 深喉 ''.
- Sex movies? - Yeah, you know, like, uh, Deep Throat.
裸体色情片. 高个, 金发碧眼, 很辣.
Skin flicks. Tall, blonde, hot.
- 非常辣. - 真的吗 ? 漂亮吗 ?
- Very hot. - Really? Good-looking?
哦, 太漂亮了. 身材很棒.
Oh, great looking. Tremendous body.
- 你好吗? - 嘿, Lenny, 你好吗?
- How you doin'? - Hey, Lenny, how are ya?
- 还好. 我可以和你谈一下吗 ? - 当然.
- Good. Can I talk to you a minute? - Yeah.
- 我需要你帮忙. - 没问题. 什么事 ?
- I need a favor. - You got it. What?
你有朋友, 嗯, 在拍成人电影, 是吗 ?
You got friends in the, uh, the adult film business, right?
我外甥和他们都认识. 怎么了 ?
My nephew knows them all. Why?
我想找一个叫Linda Ash的演员.
I'm trying to locate an actress named Linda Ash.
- 你知道她拍了什么电影吗? - 不知道.
- You know which movies she did? - No.
我在录像店想找一个电影,
I was in the video store trying to get a video,
可是, 你知道, 因为我邻居在那里 看到我, 所以我很尴尬.
but, you know, I get embarrassed because my neighbor saw me there.
- 而且 你知道-- - 我明白了.
- And, you know-- -  I hear ya.
- 好了, 我找到了再来找你. 行吗? - 好吧.
- Well, let me get back to you on that one. All right? - Yeah.
我不明白为什么我们一定要这么做.
You know, I don't know why we have to do this.
我-我不想整个星期 都待在Jerry Bender家里.
I-I don't want to spend the whole weekend at Jerry Bender's.
哦, Lenny, 拜托. 我们必须这么做.
Oh, Lenny, please. We've been through this.
那儿会有很多重要的客户.
There are lots of important clients there.
我-- 你知道, 那这是什么 ?
I-- You know, so what is this?
而且这个家伙会整个星期盯着你, 然后用意识侮辱你.
Meanwhile this guy's going to stare at you the whole weekend and mentally undress you.
他没有. 他没有.
He is not. He's not.
天哪, 你的妄想症只有历史上的 Joseph Stalin可以和你匹敌啊.
God, your paranoia is rivaled in history only by Joseph Stalin.
我很高兴你这个周末可以留下, Amanda.
I'm really glad you could make it out this weekend, Amanda.
附近有一些很重要的人 我觉得你应该认识一下.
There's some people around here I think it's very important you should meet.
哦, 谢谢, Jerry. 我很感激. 真的很感激.
Oh, thanks, Jerry. I really appreciate it. I really do.
- 天哪, 我喜欢你的帆船. - 对, 很有趣, 对吗 ?
- God, I love your sailboat. - Yeah, it's fun, isn't it?
- 对啊. - 只是很抱歉, 浪很大, Lenny.
- Yeah. - Sorry the waves were so choppy, Lenny.
哦, 没什么. 我不介意在风浪中行驶.
Oh, it's no problem. I don't mind throwing up into the wind, you know.
我们三点去看隔壁的房子.
You know, we could see that house next door at 3:00.
顺便说一下, 它值得买.
By the way, it's a great buy.
我可以打一个简短的电话吗 ?
Is it possible that I could just make one quick phone call?
- 当然可以. Ken ! - 是的, Jerry.
- Yeah. Ken! - Yes, Jerry.
哦, 不好意思, Ken. 你能带Lenny去打个电话吗 ?
Oh, sorry, Ken. Can you show Lenny the private phone?
当然可以. 走吧, Lenny. 就在那边.
Sure. Come on, Lenny. It's right over here.
听起来那个房子不错. what are they asking again ?
The house sounds exciting. What are they asking again?
Amanda, 听着. 你为什么不, 嗯, 今晚留在这儿呢.
Amanda, listen. Why don't you, uh, spend the night here tonight.
- 你说什么? 你今晚有时间吗 ? - 嗯--
- What do you say? Are you free tonight? - Uh--
我们可以坐船出去.
We could go for a sail.
你根本想不到躺在甲板上 看星星会是什么样.
You can't believe what the stars look like lying on the back of a boat.
- 是. 是想不到, 我想去. 我真的很想去. - 好, 那么就去吧.
- Yeah. No, I'd love to. I really would love to. - Well, then, do it.
可是我-- 不行, 他要回去.
But I-- No, he has to get back.
真的吗 ?
Really?
- 对. - 嗯.
- Yeah. - Hmm.
嗯.
Hmm.
我找到Linda Ash的片子了.
I got the skinny on Linda Ash.
她演过一些电影. 她不是个明星, 什么也不是.
She's been in a few films. She's no star or nothin'.
所以你从来没有听说过她.
That's why you never heard of her.
她用的是''Judy Cum''这个艺名
She works under the stage name "Judy Cum."
大多数时候, 她是个妓女.
Mostly, she's a hooker.
嗯, 我拿到她的电话了.
Uh, I got her number.
Judy Cum ?
Judy Cum?
哦, 你从来都不应该找她.
Oh, you never should have looked for her.
现在我看到一个大麻烦.
Now I see big trouble.
哦, 天哪. 你真是个卡珊德拉(凶事预言家).
Oh, for God's sake. You know, you're such a Cassandra.
我不是个卡珊德拉. 我就是卡珊德拉.
I'm not such a Cassandra. I am Cassandra.
- 那就是我. - 我一定要查出来.
- That's who I am. - I gotta check this thing out.
你会后悔的. 我现在告诉你, 赶紧放弃吧.
You'll be sorry. I'm telling you, quit now.
哦, 还有不要让Amanda 说服你买隔壁的房子.
Oh, and don't let Amanda talk you into buying the house next door.
- 这个地方 ? - 对 ! 我看到海滩侵蚀的大问题...
- This place? - Yes! I see big problems with beach erosion...
还有繁重的抵押.
and a heavy mortgage.
我喜欢那个房子.
Well, I love that property.
- 嗯. - 我们和其他人住的很近.
- Mm-hmm. - We're right near everybody.
这不代表我们要一直去看他们 可是我们可以选择.
Doesn't mean we have to see them all the time, but we have the option.
你-- 你不怕海滩侵蚀吗 ?
You-- You're not afraid of beach erosion, right?
海滩侵蚀 ? 哦, 别这样,  你现在真是个卡珊德拉.
Beach erosion? Oh, come on, now. You're such a Cassandra.
你现在要洗澡 ?
You gonna take a shower?
对. 你可以准备一下晚饭吗 ?
Yeah. Yeah, can you, uh, fix something for dinner?
好, 我来做晚饭.
Yeah, I'll make dinner.
我煮意大利面条, 可以吗 ?
I'll make the spaghetti, okay?
冰箱里有调味酱.
There's some sauce in the fridge.
喂, 请问是Linda吗 ?
Hello, is this Linda?
Linda, 嗯, 我是Lenny.
Linda, um, this is Lenny.
嗯, 我-- 我从Charlie Biggs那里拿到你的电话.
Uh, I-- I got your number from Charlie Biggs.
我想, 嗯, 可不可以...
And I wonder if, uh, it would be possible...
你明天下午有没有时间.
that you would have some time tomorrow afternoon.
- 你不应该这么做. - 别这样好吗 ?
- You shouldn't do this. - Would you please stop it?
- 你要背叛Amanda吗 ? - 我没有.
- You're gonna cheat on Amanda? - I'm not cheating.
-我只是想看看她什么样. -你会得病的.
-I just want to see what she looks like. -You can get a disease.
- 你不害怕艾滋病吗 ? - 我不会和她睡觉的.
- Aren't you scared of AIDS? - I'm not gonna sleep with the girl.
我只是想看看她什么样.
I just want to see what she looks like.
我想了解她. 这只是--
I want to get to know her or something. It's just--
嗯, 我们可以在旅馆见面吗 ?
Uh, is it possible that we could meet at a hotel?
你会在旅馆和一个妓女开房间 然后不和她睡觉吗 ?
You're gonna rent a hotel room with a hooker and not sleep with her?
别管我. 我想和她谈谈.
Leave me alone. I want to talk to her.
59号街的购物中心怎么样 ? 那--
How about the Plaza on 59th Street? Is that--
你在干什么 ? 至少应该选一个不显眼的地方.
What are you doing? At least pick an out-of-the-way spot.
哦, 天哪.
Oh, Christ.
嗯, Linda, 也许这样会更好--
Um, Linda, maybe it'd be better if I--
我去你那里 ? 那样可以吗 ?
What about your place? Would that be a possibility?
- 嗯. 嗯--
- Uh-huh. Uh--
等一下.
Hold on one second.
3点整.
3:00.
好的. 嗯, 我会去那儿的.
Okay. Um, I'll be there.
我叫Lenny.
And it's Lenny.
嗯, Lenny... Gildersleeve. 好.
Uh, Lenny... Gildersleeve. Okay.
我不相信. 太难以置信了.
I can't believe this. I can't believe it.
嗨. 你是我3点的客人吗 ?
Hi. Are you my 3:00?
- Linda Ash ? - 对, 没错.
- Linda Ash? - Yeah, that's right.
- 我是Lenny. - 你好, Lenny. 进来吧.
- I'm Lenny. - Hello, Lenny. Come on in.
- 嗯, 你是-- 你是Linda Ash, 是吗 ? - 是啊.
- Uh, you're-- you're Linda Ash, right? - Yeah.
- '我们在电话里谈过 ? - 对.
- 'Cause we spoke on the phone? - Yeah.
你还好吧 ? 你看起来很苍白.
Are you okay? You look all white.
- 我很好. - 是吗 ?
- I'm okay. - Yeah?
- 你要喝点什么吗 ?
- Do you want something to drink?
- 或者-- 你有没有一点毕雷矿泉水什么的? - 什么 ?
- Maybe-- Do you have a little Perrier or something? - What?
- 一点-- 只要一点自来水 ? - 哦, 当然. 这我有.
- Little-- Just a little tap water? - Oh, sure. I have that.
- 你真的是Linda Ash吗 ? - 是啊.
- You're definitely Linda Ash? - Yeah.
怎么了 ? 你是中风了还是什么 ?
What's the matter? Are you a stroke victim or something?
和你说过3次了. 我就是Linda Ash.
I told you three times. I'm Linda Ash.
哦.
Oh.
哦, 你房间很漂亮.
Oh, you have a, a beautiful apartment.
- 哦, 谢谢. 我自己装饰的. - 哦.
- Oh, thank you. I did it myself. - Oh.
嗯, 给你看个东西, 我刚买的.
Oh, let me show you something I just got.
- 这个. 这不是个小便人吗 ? - 哦 !
- That. Isn't it a pisser? - Ohh!
嗯, 对, 这--这个真棒.
Oh, yes, it's-- it's magnificent.
哦. 是啊. 我很有幽默感.
Oh. Well, yeah. I got a great sense of humor.
这你很快就会感觉到-- 我很有趣 而且我经得起被人开玩笑.
That's something you're going to find out about me-- I'm funny and I can take a joke.
- 很多人经不起开玩笑. - 哦, 不, 我可以.
- A lot of people can't take a joke. - Oh, no, I can.
- 他们也这么说过我. - 哦, 是吗 ?
- They say that about me too. - Oh, yeah?
- 说我很有幽默感. - 哦, 太好了 !
- That I have a good sense of humor. - Oh, good!
那你会喜欢这个. 你看, 我刚拿到的. 别人给我的.
Then you'll like this. Look, I just got this. Somebody gave it to me.
那个主要的弹簧来回活动, 这个主教就不停地 X 她的屁股.
As the main spring goes back and forth, the bishop keeps fucking her in the ass.
- 这是个真的古董, 而且时间很准. - 哦, 天哪.
- It's a genuine antique and it keeps perfect time. - Oh, my goodness.
这是个恶心的-- 哦.
It's a disgusting-- Ohh.
- Lenny ?
- Lenny?
今天的水有点黄. 你要不要喝点雪碧 ?
The water today is a little bit brown. Would you like some Sprite instead?
- 我感到有点头晕. 我-- - 哦, 不 !
- I'm feeling a little dizzy. I-- - Oh, no!
- 过来坐. - 不, 不. 我不知道为什么.
- Come sit down. - No, no. I don't know why.
知道吗, 平常我只是健康的化身.
Usually, you know, I'm just the picture of health.
- 是吗 ? 好点了吗 ? - 没有-- 不够虔诚.
- Yeah? You work out? - Not-- Not religiously.
哦, 我也不虔诚. 我们家里人大多数是主教派教友.
Oh, I'm not religious either. Mostly, my folks were Episcopalian.
- 哦, 是吗 ? 那么-- - 是啊.
- Oh, are they? So-- - So.
那你做什么呢, Lenny ? 哦, 不. 等等. 让我猜一下.
So what do you do, Lenny? Oh, no. Wait. Let me guess.
猜别人是干什么生活的 我有诀窍.
I have a great knack for guessing what people do for a living.
- 嗯-- - 嗯, 嗯-- 我会告诉你真相.
- Um-- - Um, uh-- I'll tell you the truth.
- 地毯推销员 ! - 差不多了.
- Rug salesman! - You're close.
我-- 我是个体育新闻记者. 因为--
I'm-- I'm a sportswriter. Because--
- 靠. 我连球场都没有进. - 嗯, 这不是--
- Shit. I wasn't even in the ballpark. - Well, it was not--
等一下. 球场. 体育新闻记者. 明白了吗 ?
Wait. Ballpark. Sportswriter. Get it?
- 我明白了.
-  I get it.
我曾经和一个摔跤选手那个过. 一个高大的, 多毛的家伙.
I did it with a wrestler once. A huge, hairy guy.
你一定会以为他那里会像马一样, 结果那里非常小.
You'd figure he'd be hung like a horse, but there was very little there.
等等, 我可以-- 喝一点水吗 ?
Look, could I-- could I just get a little water?
- 我不介意是不是黄的. - 哦, 不好意思.
- I don't care if it's brown. - Oh, I'm sorry.
我不介意水锈. 我只是觉得有点--
I don't mind rust. I'm just feeling a little--
告-告诉我, Linda.
T-Tell me, Linda.
嗯, 嗯, 告诉我一点你的事吧, Linda.
Uh, uh, tell me about yourself, Linda.
好吧, 你想-- 你想知道什么呢 ?
Well, what do you-- what do you want to know?
任何事情. 我只想了解你.
Anything. I just want to know about you.
- 嗯, 基本上说, Lenny, - 什么 ?
- Well, basically, Lenny, - Yes?
- 我是一个演员. - 哦, 这很好.
- I'm an actress. - Oh, that's wonderful.
我喜欢演戏. 我也在学习演戏.
I like drama. I study.
是吗 ? 嗯, 在哪里呢 ?
Yes? Uh, where-- where's that?
Paul Delucca. 你以前听说过他吗 ?
Paul Delucca. Have you ever heard of him?
- Paul Delucca ? 没有. 到现在为止应该没有. - 对.
- Paul Delucca? No. But then, I wouldn't. - Yeah.
- 哦, 他很出名. 他是个天才. - 我相信. 我相信.
- Oh, he's really well-known. He's a genius. - I'm sure. I'm sure.
他说他觉得我会出名的.
He says he thinks I'm gonna make it big.
- 嗯. - 嗯, 我知道你会的.
- Mmm. - Um, I know you will.
- 对啊. 也许你看过我的一些电影. - 有可能.
- Yeah. Maybe you've seen some of my movies. - That's possible.
你看过 ''诱人的女阴'' 吗?
Did you ever see The Enchanted Pussy?
还没有, 不过-- 它在我一定要看的片子名单里.
Not yet, but I-I-- It's on my list of must-see.
哦, 这是录像带, 你可以租到.
Oh, they're videotapes, so you can rent it.
但我真正的愿望是在百老汇演音乐剧.
But my real ambition is to be on Broadway in a musical.
- 我会唱歌. - 是吗 ?
- I sing. - Do you?
- 抱歉.
- Excuse me.
喂 ? 没空. 有些叫''嫖客''的人, 知道吗 ?
Hello? Busy. Some of them are called John, all right?
- 那是你丈夫吗 ? - 哈哈. 太可笑了.
- Was that-- Was that your husband? - Ha-ha. Very funny.
不是, 我的意思是, 你没有丈夫, 没有家庭, 没有孩子...
No, but I mean, you have no husband, no family, no children...
或是类似的什么 ?
or anything like that?
'因为有些是. 你脸上的表情很可笑.
'Cause some do. You have a funny look on your face.
- 嗯. - 我说错什么了吗 ?
- Um. - Did I say the wrong thing?
- 不. 没什么. - 我-- 我说的是--
- No. Not really. - I-- I said--
不. 不, 听着.
No. No, listen.
- 你现在有心情做什么, Len ? - 我 ? 我-我, 嗯
- What are you in the mood for, Len? - Me? I-I, well,
我想-- 我们可以聊一会儿.
I would like to-- You know, we can chat for a while.
我想我们可以慢慢来--
I thought I'd get into it slowly and, you know--
你结婚了, 是吗 ?
You're married, aren't you?
- 你怎么知道的 ? - '因为你的表情像.
- How can you tell that? - 'Cause you got that look.
表情 ? 是什么表情 ?
That look? Wh-What look is that?
那表情就像你很长时间没有 ''吹箫'' 了.
That look like it's been a long time since you've had a great blow job.
哦, 那表情. 我明白了.
Oh, that look. I-- I can understand.
- 你从哪里来的 ? - 附近.
- Wh-Where are you from? - Mm, around.
你为什么对我这么有兴趣 ?
What are you so interested in me for?
- 那是我的手指. - 我知道.
- That's my fingers. - Yes, I know.
- 这儿. - 什么--
- Here. - What--
拉 ! 把线拉开.
Pull, pull! Pull the strings.
- 把线拉开 ? - 对, 全都拉开. 看到了吗 ? 看到什么了 ?
- Pull these strings? - Yeah, pull all the strings. See? See what happens?
- 我现在没有那么呆板了. - 哦, 很简单. 这儿. 拉开.
- I'm not so mechanical as I was. - Oh, it's easy. Here. Pull.
- 啊 ! 看到了, 解开了 !  - 哦 !
- Ahh! See, it opens!  - Ohh!
太神奇了. 科学真是--
That's amazing. Science is-- is--
- 是啊. - 你, 你, 你-- 我-我--
- Yeah. - You, you, you-- I-I--
哦. 真的.
Oh. Really. Well.
你真是一个迷人的女人, 一个非常漂亮的年轻女人.
Uh, you're a very attractive woman, a very beautiful young woman.
谢谢你, Lenny.
Oh, thank you, Lenny.
你也肯可爱. 你说什么 ?
Well, you're cute too. So, what do you say?
- 你要进去洗个澡吗 ? - 洗澡 ?
- You wanna go inside, take a shower? - A shower?
-你可以亲近地对我身体好好研究一下. -哦 ! 哦.
-You can study me up close and personal. -Oh! Oh.
不, 看看, 我已经洗过了.
No, see, I bathed already.
- 你把口红都印到我--
- You got lipstick on my fi--
- 嗯, 你闻起来很干净. 嗯. - 谢谢--
- Mmm, you smell clean. Mmm. - Thank you. Well--
就像我说的, 我基本上说-- 我的耳朵.
As I say, I'm basically--  My ear.
- 你很敏感, 啊 ? - 我的耳朵是我的弱点.
- You're sensitive, huh? - It's my weak spot, in my ear.
- 哦. 好的.
- Oh. Okay.
一点点轻咬让我... 发狂.
A little nibbling makes me... go crazy.
好的, Len. 你很紧张吗 ?
Okay, Len. Are you nervous?
我-- 不是. 老实告诉你,  是, 我是很紧张.
I-- No. But yes, I am nervous, to tell you the truth.
- 可以看出来. - 我从来没有-- 我-实际上,  我从来没有这么做过.
- You do look that way. - I've never-- I-I've never done this, actually.
- 哦, 好的. 没什么. 我会慢慢来的. - 这是-- 我-我--
- Oh, okay. That's all right. I'll take it slow. - This is-- I-I--
哦. 好的. 我--
Oh. Okay. I--
嗯, 顺便告诉你, Len,
Um, incidentally, Len,
我想我应该事先告诉你 我要收200美元.
I think I should tell you ahead of time I-I get 200 dollars.
没问题. 没问题.
It's no problem. No problem.
- 只是-- 只是信用的保证. - 谢谢, Lenny. 哇 !
- Just a-- Just a show of good faith. - Thanks, Lenny. Wow!
你太好了, Len.
You're really sweet, Len.
当作宗教的捐献收下吧.
Put it down as a religious contribution.
不, 可是说真的, 你想知道为什么 我刚一开始就喜欢你吗?
No, but seriously, you want to know why I liked you right from the start?
- 为什么? - '因为我很喜欢失败者.
- Why? - 'Cause I'm always attracted to losers.
失败者 ? 你觉得我是个失败者 ?
Losers? You think I'm a loser?
是啊. 你没有自信.
Yeah. You got no confidence.
这很可爱. 我喜欢男人这样.
It's sweet. I like that in a man.
我无法忍受一些嫖客来这儿 扔下几百块钱...
I can't stand those johns who come here and throw down a couple of hundred...
然后就把东西掏出来 到处晃来晃去.
and whip out a big dick and wave it all over the joint.
哦, 我-- 即使我想,  我也不会这么做因为我只是--
Oh, I-- I wouldn't do that even if I wanted to because I'll just--
- 哦, 靠!
- Ah, shit!
喂. 哦, 你好, Angela.
Hello. Oh, hello, Angela.
哦 ! 哦, 哇 ! 哈哈 !
Oh! Oh, wow! Ha-ha!
哦, 天哪, 谢谢你想到了我.
Oh, God, thank you for thinking of me.
对, 太棒了.
Yeah, that's great.
好的. 好, 10点见.
Okay.  Yeah, well, I'll see you at 10:00.
再见.
Bye.
我刚在Angela Dawson的电影里 得到一个小角色.
I just got a small part in an Angela Dawson movie.
我要和她一起演 !
I get to do it with her!
我不太理解.
I don't understand you.
如果你-- 如果你真心想 成为一个百老汇演员,
If you're-- If you're serious about being a Broadway actress,
为什么你要在这些色情片上浪费时间?
what are you wasting your time with all this porn for?
和你有什么关系? 这是个很好的经历.
What's it to you? It's good experience.
怎么可能? 在摄像机前和一个女人那个 会是一个很好的经历?
How? Making it with a woman in front of the camera is good experience?
那会向你成为百老汇明星跨进一步吗?
That's gonna get you closer to be a Broadway star?
- 你找什么急呢 ? - 我没有着急.
- What are you getting all mad for? - I'm not mad.
我只是觉得这太疯狂了. 你是个迷人的年轻女人.
I just think it's crazy. You're an attractive young woman.
你知道, 你是-- 你没必要这样生活, Linda.
You know, what are you-- You don't have to live like this, Linda.
- 你是什么东西, 我的牧师吗? - 太疯狂了!
- What are you, my pastor? - This is crazy!
你从男人那里收钱 做所有这些事.
You take money from guys and you perform all these acts.
你知道吗, 你可以做-- 嘿, 我在说你呢.
You know, you could be-- Hey, I'm talking to you.
- 你可以有个家庭. - 嘿, 你别管我!
- You could have a family. - Hey, let go of me!
- 你可以有丈夫和孩子什么的. - 够了. 不用. 嘿 !
- You could have a husband and a child or something. - All right. No. Hey!
别做了. 现在就别做了!
Stop. Stop it now! Stop!
- 听着. 我不喜欢占有欲强的男人. - 我不是占有欲强.
- Listen. I don't like possessive men. - I'm not possessive.
你来这里, 你什么也不想和我做. 你来告诉我该做什么.
You come in here, you don't want to do anything with me. You're telling me what to do.
- 我想谈谈. - 你现在到底要不要那个?
- I want to talk. - Do you want to do it or not?
- 我想谈谈. 我付钱了, 我想谈谈. - 哦, 不. 好吧.
- I want to talk. I paid you, I want to talk. - Oh, no. Okay.
- 我买了时间了. - 那你把钱拿回去.
- I bought the time. - Then you get your money back.
- 把钱还给你. 退钱给你. - 不, 把钱留着.
- I'm giving it back. Refund. - No, keep the money.
- 走吧. 不. - 我买了时间了!
- Let's go. No. - I bought the time!
- 嘿, 够了. 现在我把钱还给你, 走吧. - 为什么我们不能谈谈?
- Hey, stop it. No, I'm giving it back and you're leaving. - Why can't I talk?
- 出去!
- Get out!
爸爸, 为什么你这样盯着我?
Daddy, why are you staring at me like that?
过来.
Come here.
你知道我为什么盯着你吗?
You know why I'm staring at you?
我盯着你 '因为我不敢相信.
I'm staring at you 'cause I can't believe it.
因为你这么聪明 你是个这么棒的孩子.
Because you're so bright and you're such a great kid.
来吧, Max. 现在该去睡觉了.
Come on, Max. Now it's time for bed.
来吧. 好了. 该去睡觉了.
Come on. Okay. Time for beddums.
- 好了吗? 这孩子越来越重了.
- Ready? The kid's getting heavy.
- 他可以自己走. - 对. 好吧. 你能走吗?
- He can walk, you know. - Yeah. Okay. Can you walk?
可怜的weinrib ! 回头吧.
Poor Weinrib! Turn back.
别再管闲事了. 接受现实吧.
Don't meddle any further. Accept the truth.
我看到灾难. 我看到了大灾难.
I see disaster. I see catastrophe.
更糟的事, 我看到了律师.
Worse, I see lawyers.
不过等等, 信使来了.
But wait, a messenger.
我来自Lenny weinrib居住的市中心,
I come from the midtown area where Lenny Weinrib,
心底强烈的改变她的激情折磨着Lenny,
tortured by passions too overwhelming to regulate,
他确实给那个妓女打了电话...
did indeed call this little hustler on the phone...
真心地希望能再见到她.
in earnest attempt to see her again.
起先他和他的这种动机''搏斗'',
At first he wrestled with his drives,
试图控制好奇心...
trying to master a curiosity...
可好奇心并没有因为第一次见面而消除, 相反变得更加强烈.
not slaked by this initial meeting, but only whetted by it.
他想更多地了解这个女人, 这个欲望 无情地驱使他再次给她打电话.
His thirst to know this woman more did inexorably provoke him to call her.
刚开始, 他只收到电话答录机的回答, 他感到不安和烦恼.
Nervous and confused, at first he only got her answering machine.
然后, 在第五次尝试时, 她终于接了电话.
Then, at fifth try, she picked up the phone herself.
可是她认为他是个疯子, 再也不想见他. 这使他觉得很痛苦不安.
Painful to relate that she thought he was nuts and did not want to meet him nohow.
''别在骚扰我, 烦人的家伙,'' 说着她就挂了电话.
"Stop bothering me, creep," was her cutting declaration.
然后她用了一个 ''F'' 打头的词.
Then she used the "F" word.
他痛苦地再次给她打电话, 提出大量的金钱补偿...
Agonized, he called again, offering her abundant financial compensation...
以换得和她简短的交谈.
just for a brief chat.
但是她拜托他别再烦她 然后狠狠地把电话摔了.
But she bade him get off her back and slammed the phone down.
最后, 怀着忧郁和无限的渴望,
Finally, in doldrums mixed with much anxiety,
他站在她住处外面...
he stood watch outside her apartment...
一直等着, 直到他看到她去自助洗衣店.
and waited until such a time as he did spot her heading for the laundromat.
- 哦, 天哪! - 好了, 别紧张什么.
- Oh, my God! - Okay, don't get upset or anything.
- 我只是想我们可以一起吃饭. - 为什么和我?
- I just thought we could have lunch. - Why me?
- 我可以付钱买你的时间. 我只想和你谈谈. - 是吗!
- I'll pay for your time. I just want to speak to you. - All right!
你是什么东西, 他妈的变态--
What are you, some kind of fucking pervert who--
离我远点. 我不是-- 我不是那种专门杀妓女的...
Leave me alone. I'm not-- I'm not one of those psychopaths...
精神病患者, 我发誓.
that kills prostitutes, I promise you.
- 你为什么要这么说我? - 开玩笑. 我开玩笑的.
- Why would you ever say something like that? - I'm joking. I'm joking.
听着, 做我这行的, 必须小心那些奇怪的人.
Listen, in my work, I have to keep an eye out for strange individuals.
- 哦. - 我知道有一个女孩被杀了.
- Okay. - I knew a girl that got killed.
是啊. 嘿, 我给你买了些花. 这儿.
All right. Hey, I got you some flowers. Here.
这些花是给你的. 我们一起吃饭吧. 我付钱.
I got you some flowers. Let's have lunch. I'll pay for it.
我会付钱买你的时间. 我只是想和你谈谈.
I'll pay for your time. I just wanna talk to you.
然后我妈妈嫁给我第三个爸爸.
So then my mother married my third father.
我的意思是, 我不知道 她有没有嫁给他, 可是他搬了进来.
I mean, I don't know if she married him, but he moved in.
我们关系不好. 他是个令人讨厌的酒鬼.
We didn't get along. He was a disgusting drunk.
你亲爸爸怎么样? 你实际上--
What about your hereditary father? Your actual, actual--
哦, 他是个毒贩子 他还是个偷车贼.
Oh, he was a drug pusher and he was also a car thief.
他偷钱包, 还入室抢劫什么的.
He picked pockets and, you know, he burgled and stuff.
- 而且他是个癫痫患者. - 哦-嗯. 你没有遗漏些什么吧, 是吗?
- And he was an epileptic. - Uh-huh. You haven't left anything out, right?
- 他还是个邮件诈骗犯 ! - 哦, 邮件诈骗犯. 哦, 这样啊.
- Mail fraud! - Oh, mail fraud. Oh, okay, yeah.
- 他就是因为这个被捕的. - 哦.
- That's what they caught him on. - Uh-huh.
嘿, 你的胃口好得像伐木工人.
Hey, you got an appetite like a lumberjack.
哦. 谢谢.
Oh. Well, thank you.
没什么. 想吃什么就吃吧.
Oh, it's fine. Eat all you want.
事实上, 我很饿了. 嗯, 然后当我14岁时我就离家出走了.
I'm very hungry, actually. Um, so then I ran away when I was 14.
哦.
Mm-hmm.
然后我和一个叫Johnny的音乐家跑了.
And I went away with this musician named Johnny.
可是我们总是争论不休, Lenny.
And it was terrible because we fought all the time, Lenny.
所以后来, 他自杀了.
Finally, he committed suicide.
这些年来, 我一直以为是 因为我的厨艺逼死了他.
And for years I thought it was because of my cooking.
他始终很讨厌我做的蛤酱.
He always hated my clam sauce.
然后呢, 我就从芝加哥,  费城开始流浪.
And so then I kicked around from Chicago, Philadelphia, you know.
到处流浪. 最后到了这里.
All over the place. And I ended up here.
你从来没想过找一份正规的工作吗?
You never thought of just getting a regular job?
哦. 当然有, 我找过. 我也做过一些.
Oh, yeah. Sure, I did. No, I did things.
我做过餐厅服务员. 做过按摩女.  还做过电话性交.
I waited on tables. I worked in a massage parlor. I did phone sex.
偶尔我还会设点局骗些钱.
Now and then I would, you know, turn a few tricks in order to make some dough.
然后有一天我的朋友Susie打电话给我 问我是否愿意演一部叫...
And one day my friend Susie calls me and she asks me if I want to be in a film.
''攫取快乐''的电影. 我说, ''当然愿意.''
Something called Snatch Happy. And I said, "Sure."
我记得当时我非常紧张...
And I remember I was very nervous...
因为你知道, 我从来没有 在拿着摄像机的人面前做过.
because I'd never done it in front of people with a camera before, you know.
那是我第一天, 第一场表演.
And so there I am on the first day, on the set.
那个男人从后面 X 我, 知道吗?
And there's this guy fucking me from behind, right?
同时还有两个穿得像警察的 男人在 X 我的嘴.
And there's these two huge guys dressed like cops in my mouth at the same time.
我记得我当时在想,
And I remember thinking to myself,
''我喜欢演戏. 我要学习演戏.''
"I like acting. I wanna study."
是啊. 真是--
Yes, well. It's a-- It's a--
这是进入一个职业的一种方式.
That's one way of getting into the profession.
嗯, 再说说你的家庭吧.
Um, tell me about your family a little bit.
什么? 我已经说过了啊. 你现在都可以写一本书了.
What? I told you already. You could write a book by now.
可是, 有没有什么特殊的成员?
But, but were there any unusual members?
- 很聪明, 很有才能之类的. - 嗯! 对!
- Very bright ones or brilliant or talented or something. - Mmm! Yes!
- 不好意思. 有. - 嗯.
- I'm sorry. There was. - Mmm.
我爸爸的哥哥应该算是个天才.
My father's brother was supposed to be a genius.
我从来没有见过他, 但是 所有人都说他很聪明.
I never met him, but everybody said he was brilliant.
- 真的吗? 他是干什么的? - 他是个连环强奸犯. 他在监狱里度过一生.
- Really? What did he do? - He was a serial rapist. He spent his whole life in jail.
但是如果他老老实实的话, 他应该在数学方面很有天分.
But if he had gone straight, he might have been very good in math.
- 数学天分. 那是-- - 对.
- Good in math. Well, that's-- - Yeah.
我想我的聪明都取自于他,
I think I got my intelligence from him,
因为我家里其他所有人都是懒汉和贱人.
because everybody else in the family is all slugs and lowlifes.
- 我是唯一有理想的人. - 是吗?
- I'm the only one with any ambition. - Are you?
那你从来-- 从来没有结婚的冲动吗?
And you never-- never had a drive to get married?
为什么要结婚? 他们都是混蛋.
What for? They're all assholes.
其中有个人常常打我.
One of them used to beat me up.
还有一个人当我不在的时候 和我最好的朋友那个.
Another one used to fuck my best friend when I wasn't looking.
- 真恶心. - 是啊.
- It was sickening. - Really.
那-- 那我问你.
And-- And let me ask you this.
你有没有什么时候想过, 就像,
At any point in your life did you ever think, like,
''也许我该要个孩子'' ?
"Maybe I'd like to have a child"?
嗯, 我有过一个孩子.
Um, I-l did have a child once.
- 是吗? - 嗯, 这是个伤心的故事.
- Did you? - Ah, it was a sad story.
等我对你多一些了解以后 我会告诉你的.
I'll tell you some other time when I know you better.
如果我会对你多些了解的话.
If I ever know you better.
你今天下午有空吗?
Are you free this afternoon?
- 干嘛? - 你下午有没有时间?
- Why? - You have some free time this afternoon?
- 你终于想做了, Lenny ? - 不, 不, 不.
- Are you finally in the mood, Lenny? - No, no, no, no, no.
我想-- 我有一个任务.
I wanna-- I have an assignment.
但我想你可能愿意和我一起去,  '因为我觉得你会喜欢的.
But I thought you might wanna come with me, 'cause I think you'll enjoy it.
我想下注在一匹马上, 如果它赢了, 钱归你.
I'm gonna bet on a horse, and if it wins you can keep the dough.
就这匹吧. ''卖力的海狸.''
Here's one. "Eager Beaver."
我以前演过一片''海狸出巡''...
I once did a film called Beaver Patrol...
是讲一些男巡逻员在森林里 发现了一些喝醉的女巡逻员.
about these Boy Scouts who find drunk Girl Scouts in the woods.
然后他们把那些女的带进小屋 然后他们翻看他们的包裹 然后他们拿出那些假阴茎.
And they take them into a cabin and they reach into their packs and they pull out these dildos.
- 然后-- - 好了, 好了. 我们--
- And then-- - All right, all right. Okay, we'll--
你确定你要押在''卖力的海狸''上?
Y-You're sure you want to bet on Eager Beaver?
- '因为赔率是60比1. - 哦, 对. 我觉得就是它了!
- 'Cause it's a 60-to-1. - Oh, yeah. No, I know it's the one. No!
- 可是赔率是60比1啊. - 这是一个预兆. 我觉得它会赢.
- But it's 60-to-1. - It's a sign. I know it's gonna work.
好的, 好的. 希望是这样.
All right, all right. Famous last words.
- 你知道. - 我有预感.
- You know. - I got a hunch.
- 你有预感. 好吧. 那我们就押它吧. - 对.
- You got a hunch. Okay. Sure, we'll bet on it. - Yeah.
好的. 那如果它赢了, 我们会赢多少?
Okay. So if he wins, how much do I make?
60比1的赔率? 嗯... 你会赢, 嗯, 3,000美元.
At 60-to-1? Uh... you make, uh, $3,000.
哦, 天哪! 我可以买那件 喜欢的蓝色南美栗鼠皮大衣!
Oh, my God! I could get that blue chinchilla coat that I wanted!
- 你爱买什么买什么. - 我可以买一个极可意按摩浴缸.
- You could get anything you want. - I could get a Jacuzzi.
- 除非它赢不了. - 哦, 不, 我知道我能做什么, Lenny!
- Except he's not gonna win. - Oh, no, I know what I could do, Lenny!
- 哦, 天哪! 太棒了. - 嗯.
- Oh, my God! This is great. - Mm-hmm.
好了. 我希望-- 我希望你是对的.
All right. You know, I hope-- I hope you're right.
虽然这匹马的赔率是60比1肯定有原因.  它可能有小儿麻痹症.
There's a reason the horse is 60-to-1, though. He's probably got polio.
哦, 不, 不. 这有预兆.
Oh, no, no. No. This is a sign.
- 好吧. - 我的运气要转了.
- All right. - My luck is gonna change.
- 那Linda是你的真名吗? 那是你真名吗? - 我用了很多名字.
- So is your real name Linda? Is that your actual name? - I use a lot of names.
我出生时叫Leslie, 但我喜欢用 有美好意味的名字.
My born name is Leslie, but I like to use names that have nice meanings.
就像Mary, 代表处女Mary.
You know, like Mary, for the Virgin Mary.
或者Angel或Linda,  在西班牙语里意思是''美丽''.
Or Angel or Linda, which means "pretty" in Spanish.
- 不过我的艺名是Judy Cum. - 嗯.
- But my screen name's Judy Cum. - Mm-hmm.
还好这些赛马中没有用这样的名字...
Well, lucky there's not a horse with that name in the race...
- '因为不然我们就会押它了. - 哦, 不, 不, 不.
- 'cause we'd bet on him. - Oh, no, no, no.
我的意思是, 那样 我的律师朋友会考虑告它.
I mean, my attorney friend would take that under advisement.
- 哦. - 我对这个名字有专属权.
- Mm-hmm. - I got exclusive rights to that name.
好的, 好的. 对.
All right, all right, all right. Yeah.
那我问你一个问题.
So let me ask you a question.
你有没有担心过一个男人 到你家里, 付给你钱...
Are you ever frightened that when a guy comes over your house and pays you...
然后他也许想, 比如把你绑起来杀了你?
that he's gonna maybe, like tie you up and kill you?
哦, 不. 我一般都事先收钱.
Oh, no. I always get paid in advance.
- 来吧.
- Come on.
- 我们买''卖力的海狸''. 他付钱. - 事先收钱? 那--
- Eager Beaver. He's paying. - Paid in advance? That's--
Lenny.
- 他们正在冲向终点 - 加油, 海狸!
-  They're coming down to the finish. -  Come on, Beaver!
- ''秋天的菊花''和''仇恨''领先. - 加油! 冲上去!
- It's Autumn Daisy and Enmity. - Come on! Catch up!
- ''卖力的海狸'' 一直落后. - 哦, 靠! 海狸!
- Eager Beaver continues to drop back. - Oh, shit! Oh, Beaver!
- ''秋天的菊花''和''仇恨''. 接近终点了. - 海狸! 加油, 海狸!
- Autumn Daisy and Enmity. It's close. - Beaver! Come on, Beaver!
- 哦! 海狸! - ''秋天的菊花''领先一个头获胜.
- Oh! Beaver! - It's Autumn Daisy by a head.
- 靠! 最后一个? - ''仇恨''第二个跑到终点...
- Shit! Last? - Enmity finishing second...
- ''降旗''第三, - 该死的笨马--他妈的!
- and Lower The Flag finishing third, - Stupid horse got-- Damn it!
- 接下来是''马希的骄傲'', ''真正的蓝水手'', ''一流警报'', - 早知道我花了那些钱!
- followed by Marcy's Pride, True Blue Crew, Classic Alert, - I had it spent already!
- 我知道. 放松, 放松, 可以吗? - ''卖力的海狸''最后一个到达终点.
- I know. Relax, relax. Relax, will ya? - and Eager Beaver was last.
这并不是太糟. 我说过这是个风险大的赌注.
You know, it's not so terrible. I told you it was a long shot.
- 我从来都不走运. 从来都不 ! - 好了.
- I never have any luck. Never! - All right.
我这一辈子从来没他妈的赢过什么!  什么也没有! 从来没有!
I never won a fucking thing in my entire life! Nothing! Never!
你可以冷静一点吗? 你要学会做一个优雅的失败者.
Will you stay calm? You gotta learn to be a graceful loser.
如果是因为钱, 我可以把钱借给你.
If it's the money, I'll lend you the money.
- 我可以帮你. - 不, 不是因为钱, Lenny.
- I can help you. - No, it's not the money, Lenny.
我不在乎那些钱. 我只是太想赢了.
I don't care about the money. I just wanted to win so badly.
你为什么就想赢呢? 我们来这里玩得开开心心的.
What do you want to win for? We're just out here having a good time.
- 你应该-- - '因为我想打动你.
- You gotta-- - 'Cause I wanted to impress you.
打动我? 什么?  你又没有在比赛中跑.
Impress me? What? You know, you're not running in the race.
什么-- 你不需要打动我. 我--
What-- You don't have to impress me. I'm--
对, 可是我想证明 我可以选一个胜利者.
Yeah, but I wanted to show you I could pick a winner.
嘿. 听着, 我选的马也没有赢.
Hey. Listen, my horse didn't win either, you know.
好了, 你-- 你确实打动了我.
Come on, you-- you do impress me.
你很迷人, 你-- 你很活泼, 你充满活力.
You're attractive, you're-- you're quick, you have a lot of energy.
- 你很明显是个高水平的口交者. - 什么?
- You're obviously a state-of-the-art fellatrix. - What?
嗯-- 没什么, 没什么. 我被打动了. --
So-- Nothing, nothing. I'm impressed. Take--
- Lenny, 不要说''没什么.'' - 我被打动了.
- Lenny, don't say "nothing." - I'm impressed.
- 你以为我很蠢吗? - 我不认为你很蠢, 不.
- You think I'm stupid? - I don't think you're stupid, no.
- 不? - 我觉得你这样生活很傻.
- No? - You know, I think you do a stupid thing with your life.
可是我已经告诉过你了.
But I told you that already.
我不明白这和你有什么关系呢.
Well, I don't understand why it matters so much to you.
嘿, 好了. 我们留下来再赌一次,  这次我为你下注.
Hey, come on. We'll stay for one more race, and this time I'll bet for you.
- 是吗? - 让我来下注. 对. 来吧.
- Yeah? - Let me make the bet. Yeah. N-No. Come on.
- 我们去窗口那里, 我来下注. - 好吧.
- We'll just go to the window and I'll make one bet. - All right.
最好不要挑个第二名...
Please don't pick one that runs second...
- '因为我想要胜利者, 好吗, Len ? - 好. 嘿.
- 'cause I want a winner, okay, Len? - Yeah. Hey.
不过你知道, 他们给这些马进行 唾液测试. 我不能保证什么.
You know, they give these horses saliva tests. I can't guarantee anything.
- 我把你赢的给你了, 是吧? - 对.
- I gave you your winnings, right? - Yeah.
这次比赛很棒. 可惜那匹马只给40美分.
That was a great race. Too bad the horse only paid 40 cents.
它真是一个幸运儿, 知道吗, 我押他跑第三名呢.
Well, he was a heavy favorite, you know, and I bet him to come in third.
- 至少这样你赢了一些. - 对.
- At least this way you get something. - Yeah.
嗯, 你要进来吗?
So, you wanna come in?
我要回家了. 我有老婆孩子. 我不能这么做.
I gotta go home. I got a wife and kid. You know, I can't.
你只谈我. 你从来不谈你自己.
You know, you only talk about me. You never talk about yourself.
太晚了. 知道吗, 我今天很开心, 但我要走了.
It's late for me. You know, I had a great time, but I gotta go.
我觉得我欠你那个一次.
I feel I owe you a great fuck.
嘿, 帮帮忙. 上楼去吧, 休息一下, 今晚待在家里.
Hey, do me a favor. Go upstairs, rest your ulcer, stay in tonight.
我不能待在家里. 我还有6个约会.
I can't stay in. I got six dates.
6个约会. 漫长的夜晚, 是吗?
Six dates. Slow night for you, right?
我想要是我在你房里有青霉素特许权.  我会--我会发财的.
I wish I had the penicillin concession in your apartment. I'd-- I'd be wealthy.
好吧. 那, 你会再给我打电话吗?
All right. So, you're gonna call me again?
我会再给你打电话吗? 对, 我会给你打电话. 别担心.
Am I gonna call you again? Yeah, I'll call you. Don't worry.
- 你保证? - 我会的. 我会再给你打电话的.
- You promise? - I will. I'll call you again.
好吧. 我今天很开心.
Okay. I had a great time.
- 再见. - 好的.
- Bye. - Okay.
吆.
Whew.
- 恭喜你. - 35年了.
- Congratulations. - Thirty-five years.
- 我从来没想过我们会在一起这么久. - 你和Amanda...
- I never thought we'd make it. - You and Amanda...
还有很长的路要走, 可是你们也会做到的.
have a way to go, but you'll make it.
- 你们还这么年轻, 两个都是. - 对, 你们都很年轻.
- You guys look so young, both of you. - Yeah, you do.
我们让彼此都很年轻.
Well, we've kept each other young.
你妈妈可以成为你姐姐, 你们可以成为兄妹.
Your mother could be your sister, and you could be brother and sister.
- 你可以成为我的-- 是啊. - 我不知道该说什么, 不管怎么样--
- You could be my-- yes. - I don't know where that puts me, but anyway--
她看起来真美, 是吗, Lenny ?
She looks so beautiful, doesn't she, Lenny?
- 对我来说, 她总是这么美. - 嗯.
- To me, she always looks beautiful. - Mmm.
-我总是觉得她很棒. 还有你--
-I just always find her great. And you--
以前当我说姐妹时, 我就是这个意思. 你们看起来都这么棒.
When I said sisters before, I mean it. You guys look so great.
太神奇了, 带着所有这些责任...
And it's a wonder, with all the responsibility...
她开了属于自己的新画廊.
she has opening her new gallery.
- 有很多事情要做. - 什么新画廊? 一个新画廊?
- It's a lot of work. - What new gallery? A new gallery?
不, 我没有告诉你 '因为, 我不知道 要到100%确定才可以.
No, I didn't tell you 'cause, you know, I don't know until it's a hundred percent definite.
- 哦, 我说了什么不该说的吗? - 可是还没有.
- Well, did I say the wrong thing? - But it's not.
- 不, 当然不是. 不, 我只是-- - 要100%确定.
- No, sure. No, I just-- - It's a hundred percent definite.
你这么不放心. 现在成功了.
You're so insecure. It's happening.
- 嗯, 不好意思.
- Oh, excuse me.
- 这发生了什么? - 看起来好像我有资助者,
- What is the story on this? - It looks like I have the backing,
但还没有完全确定.
but it's not totally definite.
- 所以我才什么也没说. - 你妈妈说已经确定了.
- That's why I didn't say anything. - Your mother said it was definite.
对, 嗯. 看起来如果我确实有资助.
Yeah, well. It seems as if I do have the backing.
还有在维奇街这么合适的地方. 你知道吗?
And there is this wonderful space on Vesey Street. You know it?
- 维奇? 对, 我知道. - 对, 在休南区.
- Vesey? Yeah, I know it. - Yeah, down in Soho.
看起来好像,  我们觉得我们可以买下来.
And it looks like, you know, we think we can get it.
Dorians夫妇投资了一些钱,  不过我--
The Dorians are putting in some money, but I--
- 你看起来不是很开心. - 我很开心!
- Well, don't look so happy about it. - I am happy!
我为你感到开心, 可是你知道, 我刚刚才听说这些,
I'm very happy for you, but it's the first I'm hearing of it, you know.
- 而且还是你妈妈告诉我的-- - 对, 听着.
- And for your mother to tell me-- - Yeah, well, look.
我意识到暂时我会比平常更忙一些...
I realize that for a time I'm going to be busier than usual...
我也知道这会是个难关,
and I know that's a sore point,
可是, 你知道, 只有到 '到它真正开放了.
but, you know, it'll be only 'til it gets off the ground.
- 嘿, 我为你感到开心. 我真的-- - 你开心吗?
- Hey, I'm happy for you. I re-- - You are?
- 是啊. 我只是想我终于知道了. - 你确定?
- Yes. I just would have liked to have known it. - Are you sure?
- Amanda Sloane画廊. 我觉得这很棒. - 对, 在维奇街.
- The Amanda Sloane Gallery. I think that it's great. - Yeah, on Vesey Street.
相信我. 我连Jerry Bender都没有告诉.
Believe me. I haven't even told Jerry Bender yet.
''你有绝对的权利,  像你对待母亲的方式,
"You've got a fine right, you have, after the way you treated Mother,
''像你对待我们所有人的方式!
"after the way you treated us all!
''以你最好的国家礼仪, 你有绝对的权利回到这里...
"A fine right you've got to come back in here in your best country manner...
''打击意见, 发表立场...
"and strike attitudes and make stands...
''批评我的未婚夫 发号施令...
"and criticize my fiance and give orders...
''把事情弄得一团糟 好像你--
"and mess things up generally as if you'd done--
''够了, 我受不了了. 太恶心了!
"Well, I can't help it. It's sickening!
就像他什么也没做过!''
As if he'd done nothing at all!"
嗯?
Well?
你觉得怎么样?
What do you think?
- 什么怎么样? - 我啊.
- About what? - About me.
- 你觉得我演得好不好? - 是, 很好.
- You think I'm any good? - Yes, it's fine.
我-- 你知道吗, 你问错人了.
I-- You know, you're asking the wrong person.
实话告诉你, 我并不是很了解演戏.
I don't know that much about acting, to tell you the truth.
哦, 我看得出来你没有太感兴趣.
Oh, I can tell you're not too impressed.
不, 不, 不. 我只是在想, 你选的是个很奇怪的角色.
No, no, no. I just thought, you know, it's a very odd part for you to choose.
- 为什么? - 嗯, '因为这个是''费城故事''.
- Why? - Well, you know, 'cause it's The Philadelphia Story.
- 我住在费城啊. - 和这个有什么关系?
- But I lived in Philadelphia. - What has that got to do with it?
- 我知道这个城市. - 什么? 你这么挑角色--
- I know the city. - What? You pick a part like this--
你应该挑和你自己接近的. 那就不会像这样困难.
You should get something closer to yourself. It wouldn't be such a struggle.
- 嗯, 那我该选什么角色?
- You know. - Well, what part should I play?
我不知道--和你接近的.
You know-- I don't know. Something closer.
Clint Eastwood不会演 一个温顺的小美容师.
Clint Eastwood doesn't play a meek little hairdresser.
嗯, 我可以演美容师.
Well, I could play a hairdresser.
我-我过去-- 我过去经常做.
I-I used to-- I used to do it a lot.
我想成为一个美容师. 我很擅长这个.
I wanted to be one. I was very good at it.
- 那你为什么放弃了呢? - 我不知道.
- So why'd you give it up? - Well, I don't know.
事情一件接一件发生.
One thing led to another.
我阿姨在美容院干了好几年.
You know, my aunt worked in a beauty parlor for years.
她很喜欢这个.
She loved it.
等等. 你的意思是不当演员了?
Wait. You mean not be an actress?
演员是个很艰难的生活, 知道吗.
Well, an actress is a very tough life, you know.
- 可是美容师总是可以赚很多钱. - 很多钱?
- But a hairdresser could always make a buck. - A buck?
很多钱! 很多干净钱. 没有打人, 没有艾滋病.
A buck! An honest buck. No beatings, no AIDS.
你可以认识一些--
You can meet somebody that you, you know--
你可以有个家庭, 有真正的生活, 有个关心你的人.
You can get a family, have a real life, someone that cares for you.
嘿!
Hey!
你以为我不想认识某些人, 然后结婚吗...
Now, don't you think that I want to meet somebody and get married...
离开这该死的你死我活的斗争?
and get the hell out of the rat race?
我想离开这里 好好做个母亲, 养孩子.
I would like to move away and become a mother and just raise kids.
我连美容师也不想做.
I don't even want to be a hairdresser.
如果Clint Eastwood想当美容师,  就让他去做吧.
If Clint Eastwood wants to be a hairdresser, just let him.
你误会我的意思了. Clint Eastwood 不想成为一个美容师.
You missed the point. Clint Eastwood doesn't want to be a hairdresser.
我有过一个孩子, Lenny,
I had a kid, Lenny,
我把他送人收养了.
and I gave him up for adoption.
这是我这一生做过的最遗憾的事e.
It's the sorriest thing I ever did in my entire life.
没有一天我不会...
There's not a day that doesn't go by that I don't...
因为想到他半夜醒来.
wake up thinking about him.
现在某个幸运的家庭拥有他.
Now some lucky family has him.
我只求上帝保佑他们好好照顾他.
I just hope to God that they're taking good care of him.
为什么你放弃他呢?
Why'd you give him up?
我不知道. 我当时-- 我当时很困惑.
I don't know. I was-- I was all confused.
我没有钱. 我-我-- 我不知道该怎么办.
I had no dough. I-I-- I didn't know what to do.
我--
I--
我连谁是他父亲都不知道.
I didn't even know who the father was.
可能是几百个男人中的任何一个.
It could've been any one of a hundred guys.
欢迎来到地球, 感谢那个破掉的避孕套.
Welcome to planet Earth, thanks to a broken condom.
哎呀. 这太难了.
Gee. That's tough.
嗯.
Um.
你的孩子怎么样?
What about your kid?
Max ? 你知道吗. Max是最棒的.
Max? M-M-Ma-- You know. Max is the greatest.
- 是吗? - 嗯, 当然.
- Yeah? - Well, sure.
你有他的照片吗?
Do you have a picture of him?
- Max的照片? - 对. 我想看看他.
- A picture of Max? - Yeah. I'd like to see him.
哦.
Oh.
嗯, 对, 我想我--
Uh, yeah, I guess I--
哦.
Oh.
他很可爱. 他--
He's very sweet. He--
你很幸运.
You're very lucky.
和Amanda一起, 这是运气.
With Amanda, it was fate.
和Linda一起, 那是自以为是.
With Linda, it's hubris.
他查出真相的动机, 现在, 变成改变她的生活, 支配她.
His drive to find out, and now, to change her life, to control her.
- 是啊. - 危险.
-  Yes. -  Danger.
等等. 我看到了... 危险.
Wait. Wait, I see... danger.
嘿, 等一下. 我没有支配她的兴趣.
Hey, wait a minute. I don't have any interest in controlling her.
我是为了Max才这么做的.
I'm doing this for Max's sake.
当他长大了, 不可避免地要去找他母亲.
When the kid gets older, inevitably he's gonna trace his mother.
然后, 知道吗, 我会更高兴...
And, you know, I'd be happier...
如果她结婚了或者是个美容师,
if she was married and a-- a hairdresser, you know,
而不是什么''诱人的女阴''的明星.
rather than the star of The Enchanted Pussy.
危险! 我看到了可怕的, 可怕的危险!
Danger! I see horrible, horrible danger!
- 可怕的危险! - 嘿, 我会在情绪上处理好的.
- Terrible danger! - Hey, I can handle myself emotionally.
不是情绪的危险, 是身体的危险.
Not emotional danger, physical danger.
我看到一个秃头的男人. 他有一根铅管.
I see a bald man. He has a lead pipe.
他打断你的膝盖骨.
He's breaking your kneecaps.
那, 那, 嗯-- Jerry Bender怎么表现的...
So, so, uh, what did, uh-- How did Jerry Bender take it...
当你告诉他最后的决定时?
when you said that the decision was final?
知道吗? 他很吃惊.
You know what? He was amazing.
我以为他会不高兴, 可是没有, 他很兴奋, 很支持.
I thought he'd be upset, but no, he was very excited and very supportive.
不, 他-- 他对此反应绝对很好.
No, he's being-- He was absolutely great about it.
不管怎样, 我-我打电话告诉你 我今晚不去吃饭了.
Anyway, I-l'm calling to say I can't make dinner tonight.
哦, 你在开玩笑. 今晚会很棒.
Oh, you're kidding. It's gonna be great.
麦迪逊广场公园组织的所有人都会去.
Everybody in the Madison Square Garden organization's gonna be there.
听着, 肯定不行 我走不开.
Look, there's no way I can get away.
建筑师在这儿 Dorians夫妇从巴黎过来.
The architects are here and the Dorians are in town from Paris.
还有, 嗯, 那些建筑师今晚飞回米兰.  我去不了.
And, uh, the architects fly back to Milan tonight. I can't.
好吧, 嗯. 我跟你说.
All right, well.  I'll tell you what.
我会回家,  我会照顾Max睡觉.
What I'll do is, I'll go home and I'll put Max to sleep.
我会去那儿待一会儿时间, 然后--
I'll spend a little time there and then--
然后-- 哦.
Then-- Oh.
嗯, 听着, 我-- 我会再给你打电话. 我要, 嗯--
Uh, look, let me-- I'm gonna call you back. I got, uh--
我会再给你打电话. 哦, 这样.
I'm gonna call you back. Oh, geez.
- 这不符合我们的规定-- - 我明白!
It's just against our policy-- -  I understand!
- 如果你愿意在这里等. - 随便.
- If you wanna wait right here. - Whatever.
-Lenny, 这儿有个人想见你. -Lenny!
-Lenny, there's someone here to see you. -Lenny!
- 嗯, 是. 嗯, 进-进来. 进来. - Lenny!
-  Uh, yes. Uh, c-c-come in. Come in. - Lenny!
- 这-这是Gildersleeve小姐. 她是熟人. - 你认识她?
- Th-This is Miss Gildersleeve. She's an acquaintance. - You know her?
- Gildersleeve? - 是, 小姐--Gildersleeve小姐.
- Gildersleeve? - Yes, Miss-- Miss Gildersleeve.
我们是老-- 没事. 没事. 我马上出来.
We're old-- It's okay. It's okay. I'll be in here.
- 你不需要什么吗? - 不, 不! 我很好.
- You don't need anything? - No, no! I'm fine.
- 好吧. - 我很好.
- Okay. - I'm fine.
- 你在这儿干嘛? - Lenny? Lenny, 我要和你谈谈.
- What are you doing here? - Lenny? Lenny, I got to talk to you.
Ricky威胁说--说-- 他要伤害我. 他--
Ricky threatened to-- to-- to hurt me. He--
- 谁是Ricky ? - 他从我工作中提成.
- Who's Ricky? - He takes a percentage of my work.
- 他是拉皮条的, 是吗? - 不, 他像一个商业代表.
- He's a pimp, right? - No, he's like a business representative.
你要商业代表干什么-- 你--你--
What do you need a business repre-- You-- You--
你需要的只是一个床垫和一些吊袜腰带. 你们又不是集团公司.
All you need is a mattress and a couple of garter belts. You're not a conglomerate.
Lenny, 他说他 要砍了我...
Lenny, he said he was going to cut me up...
因为我告诉他我不想再干了.
because I told him I didn't want to work anymore.
嗯, 我觉得你想退出是个好主意.
Well, I think it's a great idea that you want to phase out.
- 他肯定会杀了我的. - 哦.
- He has no qualms about killing me. - Ohh.
听着, 我们报警. 没什么大不了的.
Listen, we'll call the police. That's not a big deal.
以我的身份怎么能报警呢?
How can I call the police with my setup?
我和你说过无数次...
You know, I told you a thousand times...
你干的是危险的工作.
you're in a hazardous business.
你看现在怎么样. 现在, 这样-- 不要出去了.
So that's what happens. Now, so-- Don't go outside.
我不会出去了. 我想, 也许你可以和他谈谈.
I'm not going outside. I thought, just maybe, if you could talk to him.
- 我? 什么, 你疯了吗? - 对, 因为--
- Me? What, are you nuts? - Yeah, because--
因为你很聪明 你说话很有技巧.
Because you're smart and bright and you got a way with words.
我不能和他谈. 我根本都不认识他.
I can't talk to him. I don't even know the guy.
对, 嗯, 他知道我想退出不干 全是你的主意.
Yeah, well, he knows it was your idea that I get out of the business.
所以他说他也要杀了你.
So he said he's gonna kill you too.
- 他说他要杀了我? - 对, '因为这是你的主意.
- He said he was gonna kill me? - Yeah, 'cause it was your idea.
他要划花我的脸 然后把子弹射进你的眉心.
He's gonna cut up my face and put a bullet between your eyes.
真的吗? 他-- 他有没有说是什么口径?
Really? Did he-- Did he specify the caliber?
听着, 我想也许 你可以说服他.
Listen, I just thought maybe you could just reason with him.
不, 我不能. 我-- 听着, 我从来没有告诉你这些,
No, I can't. I-- Listen, I never told you this,
我有-- 轻微的心杂音...
but I got a-- a slight heart murmur...
现在那个杂音告诉我''躲起来.''
and right now it's murmuring "hide."
- 我不相信你是个懦夫.
- I don't believe you're a coward.
只有在现实中. 嗯, 这个我办不到.
Only in actuality. Um, this is not for me.
- Lenny, 我需要你的帮助. - 你, 我不是一个暴力的人.
- Lenny, I need your help. - No, I'm not a violence person.
我-我写曲棍球, 拳击和橄榄球的报道.  这不是我的事.
I-I write about hockey and boxing and football. This is not my world.
Lenny, 我真的想像你说的那样退出, 但他说他不会让我退出的!
Lenny, I do want to quit like you said, but he said he's not gonna let me!
- 他会伤害我们俩的. 求求你! - 放松, 放松.
- He's gonna hurt us both. Please! - Relax, relax.
你想我做什么? 我该怎么和他谈?
What do you want me to do? How am I gonna talk to him?
- 嗯, 好的. 你只要-- - 我--
- Well, okay. You just-- - I--
你只要和他谈, 因为你比他聪明 也比他强壮.
You just talk because you're smarter than he is and stronger than he is.
你是一个很好的人. 所以只要 在你和他谈的时候记住这些.
You're a much better man. So just remember that when you talk to him.
他只是吓唬人. 他秃头, 戴着个耳环.
He's a little bit intimidating. He's got a bald head and an earring.
- 你会赢的. 我知道你会的. - 他妈的, 我--我--
- But you'll win. I know you will. - Jesus, I-- I--
你是个好人, Lenny. 你会赢的.
You're a good man, Lenny. You'll win.
听着, 万一发生了什么事,
Look, in case anything comes up,
我想让你知道我-我是O型血 -阳性, 知道了吗 ?
I want you to know that I-l'm type O-positive, okay?
Derek, I got the feeling you came here and obviously moved...
into this whole Knick persona.
- 不好意思.
- Did you get caught up, maybe, with a little bit of this Knick, - Excuse me.
"I gotta be physical, I gotta be tough," and maybe--
我是Gildersleeve., 嗯,  我是Lenny Gildersleeve.
I'm, uh, I'm Lenny Gildersleeve.
我--我是Linda--Linda Ash的朋友.
I-- I'm a friend of Linda-- Linda Ash's.
嗯, 我想也许我们可以--
And, uh, I thought that perhaps we could--
你看--
See--
我想和你谈的是...
What I want to discuss with you is that...
每一个年轻女人的生活中 都会有一个时间,
there comes a time in the life of every young woman,
不只是Linda, 而是每一个人,
not just Linda, but everyone,
她们--她们觉得也许可以改变一下.
that they-- they want to perhaps make a change in their life.
她们也许想安定下来 寻找另一种生活方式.
They maybe want to settle down or explore alternative lifestyles.
我不觉得你对Linda是一个很好的影响, weinrib先生.
I don't think you've been a very good influence on Linda, Mr. Weinrib.
weinrib. 对. Gildersleeve是我 工作需要所用的一个名字.
Weinrib. Right. So Gildersleeve is a name I use for business purposes.
- 我对Linda有投资. - 没有问题.
- I got an investment in Linda. - No question.
我对此表示敬意. 不过-- 不过现在, 她可能...
I honor that. But-- But by now, she's probably...
已经十倍或者二十倍或者--
repaid you tenfold or twentyfold or--
别他妈这么确定, '因为你不知道 他妈的数目是多少!
Don't be so fuckin' sure, 'cause you don't know what the fuckin' numbers are!
就是这一点. 不好意思, 你--你--不好意思.
That's a point well taken. Excuse me, you're-- you're-- Excuse me.
我-我-我明白你的意思. 这是Pellegrino酒吗 ?
I-I-I understand what you're saying. Is that a Pellegrino?
我可以-- 因为你揪得我的喉咙有点.
Can I-- Because you've bent my throat now a little bit.
嗯, 气管刚才还一直是直通的.
And, uh, the windpipe used to hang straight until this moment.
他妈的尼克斯队!
The fuckin' Knicks suck!
他们需要很好的直传.
They need a good shootin' forward.
对, 嗯, 会有一个三方交易.
Yes, well, there's gonna be a three-way trade.
我不知道你们听说过吗.
I don't know if you guys heard anything about it.
- 西雅图, 亚特兰大和尼克斯在讨论. - 放屁.
- Seattle, Atlanta and the Knicks are talking. - Bullshit.
- 不, 不, 不. 没有开玩笑. 我知道. 还没决定. - 是吗?
- No, no, no. I kid you not. I know. It's in the air. - Yeah?
- 他们在商量一个交易. - 那你觉得新泽西网队怎么样?
- They're discussing a trade. - So what do you think about the Nets?
- 你觉得新泽西网队有机会吗? - 新泽西网队? 是, 我觉得有.
- You think the Nets got a chance? - The Nets? Yes, I do.
如果他们没人受伤, 我想他们很有机会.
If they're injury-free, I think they have a good chance.
我喜欢新泽西网队. 我想他们 有一两年出局, 就这些了.
I like the Nets. I think they're one or two years away, is all.
我觉得应该有两三年.
I would say two or three myself.
看到没有, 我们三个人, 我们有共同的兴趣.
You see, we have a common interest, the three of us.
- 我们刚才说到哪里? - Linda, Linda Ash.
- What were we talking about? - Linda, Linda Ash.
哦, 对, 对. 那个女孩哪里也不能去.
Oh, yeah, yeah. That girl's goin' no place.
她背叛我, 我要毁她的容 我他妈还要杀了你.
She walks on me, I'll disfigure her and I'll fuckin' kill you.
你看, Kleinholtz博士称之为''付诸行动.''
See, that's exactly what Dr. Kleinholtz would call "acting out."
- 别他妈的告诉我该怎么做! - 我没有!
- Don't tell me how to run my fuckin' business! - I'm not!
我的女孩要做我让她们去做的事.
My girls do what I tell 'em to do.
我没有要建议你该怎么做.
Far be it for me to advise you.
很明显你有适合你需要的工作道德规范.
You obviously have a work ethic that's specific to your needs.
这就是为什么你可以建立这么一个公司.
That's why you can afford an establishment like this, you know.
你要忍受他这么对你?
You're gonna take that from him?
冷静点. 冷静点.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
我将在这里有个体外经历.
I'm about to have an out-of-body-experience here.
- 展示你的力量. - 展示我的力量?
- Show strength. - Show strength?
这个家伙会把我分成27块装在玻璃瓶里.
This guy's gonna put me into 27 separate Mason jars.
那个女孩说得对. 她们崇拜力量.  她们轻视懦弱.
The girl was right. They respect strength. They despise cowardice.
他们只知道力量. 勇敢地站起来.
Power is all they know. Stand firm.
- 想想勇敢的阿基里斯. - 嘿, 别--
- Remember brave Achilles. - Hey, don't get--
阿基里斯只有阿基里斯之踵一个弱点. 而我有阿基里斯身体所有弱点.
Achilles only had an Achilles heel. I have a full Achilles body.
- 继续!
- Go on!
你看, 我和你说实话.
Look, I'm gonna level with you.
我想谈谈Linda Ash的事 我-我--
I want to discuss this Linda Ash thing and I-I--
你为什么对Linda这么感兴趣, 啊?
What are you so interested in Linda for anyway, huh?
- 你干过她? - 不, 我们是纯柏拉图的关系.
- Are you fuckin' her? - No, we have a strictly platonic relationship.
- 是吗? - 很好的衬衣啊.
- Yeah? - It's a good shirt.
如果你是她的朋友,  别和她说什么愚蠢的想法.
Well, if you're a friend of hers, don't be putting stupid ideas in her head.
她会因此受伤害的. 你也是.
She's liable to get hurt. You too.
你就让他那么对你吗?
You're gonna let him do that to you?
嘿, 听着. 帮帮忙 回到雅典去?
Hey, look. Would you do me a favor and go back to Athens?
你就让你儿子的母亲 做这个拉皮条的白人妓女吗?
You gonna let your son's mother remain a white slave to this two-bit pimp?
这--开始要这么看了, 对吗?
It-- It's starting to look that way, isn't it?
- 你弄到尼克斯比赛的票了吗? - 没有票.
- You get them Knicks tickets yet? - No tickets.
- 我到处都试过了.
- I tried everywhere.
- 你要尼克斯比赛的票吗? 因为我-- - 怎么样? 你知道谁?
- Do you need tickets to the Knicks game? Because I-- - Why? Who do you know?
我? 我-我可以帮你.
Me? I-I can help you.
我们要电影明星后面那排的座位.
We want seats on the floor, next to the movie stars.
如果你愿意谈谈Linda的交易, 我可以给你球场边缘的座位票.
If you want to discuss a deal with Linda, I can get you courtside seats.
你能拿到那些票. 没有人能拿到那些票, 因为我试过了.
You can't get 'em. Nobody can get 'em, 'cause I tried.
不, 我可以. 我--我是个体育新闻记者. 我可以拿到.
No, I can, though. I-- I'm a sportswriter. I can get 'em.
你他妈的帮我妈妈弄到球场边缘的票,
I'd fuckin' give you my mother for courtside seats,
那个不值钱的妓女算什么.
much less this cheap little whore.
太完美了, 太简洁了. 我知道你什么意思了.
That's perfectly put, succinctly put. I know what point you're making.
- 如果你他妈的想推掉什么, - 冷静, 一点--
- But if you're tryin' to fuckin' pull something, - Easy. Take it--
我会开枪从你和她眼珠里射进去!
I will shoot you and her through the fuckin' eyeballs!
在细节上讨价还价太无聊了.
It's silly to haggle over details.
嗯, 我会弄到那些票的. 我保证, 我会弄到那些票的.
Well, I'll get the tickets. I'll get the tickets, I promise.
然后我们再来谈Linda的事.
Then we can discuss Linda.
爸爸, 你很勇敢吗?
Dad, are you very brave?
我勇敢吗? 你问这个问题太可笑了.
Am I brave? It's funny you should ask that question.
那你和迈克.泰森打，谁会赢?
Who'd win a fight, you versus Mike Tyson?
什么? 什么? 谁会赢什么?
What? What? Who would win what?
那你和迈克.泰森打，谁会赢?
Who'd win a fight, you versus Mike Tyson?
- 我和迈克.泰森? 你觉得谁会赢? - 你吗?
- Me versus Mike Tyson? Who do you think would win? - You?
毫无疑问.
There'd be no contest, you know.
前几轮他可能会赢, 但我最终会击败他.
He would probably take the early rounds, but I'd get to him eventually.
我会在整个拳击场追着他打. 这是我的风格. 一直都是.
I'd chase him all over the ring. It's my style. Always was.
大体上, 我认为这样可以.  对, 我觉得可以.
On the whole, I think it will work. Yeah, I think it will.
唯一一件事就是, 我想画廊从顶部照明,
The only thing is, I want the gallery to be lit from above,
所以我觉得天窗应该加大.
so I guess the skylight will have to be enlarged.
- 亲爱的? 可以上床了吗? - 我还是他?
- Honey? Bed? Could you? - Me or him?
他. 好吗?
Him. Please?
不, 对不起, 对不起. 我不能这么做. 我不能.
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I can't do this. I can't.
-你为什么这么抗拒呢? -'因为我结婚了, 我有家庭.
-Why are you fighting this? -'Cause I'm married and I have a family.
而且我爱Lenny.
A-And I love Lenny.
我爱他.
I love him.
那么, 你想说服谁呢, 你还是我?
So, who are you trying to convince, you or me?
- 我给你买了个礼物. - 你在开玩笑吧.
- I got you a present. - You're kidding.
真的. 因为你解决了我和Ricky之间的事.
Yeah. For fixing things up with me and Ricky.
- 我知道他一定很粗暴. - 这完全没有必要.
- I know he can be really rough. - That was completely unnecessary.
很可爱, 可是完全没有必要.
Very sweet, but completely unnecessary.
你不想要口交, 所以至少我可以给你买一条领带.
You didn't want a blow job, so the least I could do was get you a tie.
想得对. 这--嗯!
Good thinking. That's uh-- Oh!
- 是, 这个条领带, 是吗?
- Yes, it's a tie, isn't it?
- 你会穿这么鲜艳的吗? - 如果场合需要的话.
- Would you ever wear anything that bright? - If the occasion demanded.
就像如果我被邀请参加四月斋戒, 我会--
You know, like if I ever get invited to the Mardi Gras, I could--
哦, 太好了. Lenny, 你要三明治吗?  我要吃个三明治.
Oh, good. Lenny, do you want a sandwich? I'm gonna have a sandwich.
- 不用, 我很好. 谢谢. - 哦, 好吧.
- No, I'm fine. Thank you. - Oh, okay.
- 很不错. - 太好了.
- It's great. - Good.
你知道吗, Lenny ?
You know what, Lenny?
我无法忘记你孩子的照片.
I couldn't get your son's picture out of my mind.
- 嗯, 他很可爱. - 是啊.
- Well, he's a very cute kid, you know. - Yeah.
Len ?
Len?
我想我会是个好母亲.
I think I would be a good mother.
我想你会是个好母亲的. 你这么有爱心.
I think you'd be a great mother. You're very affectionate.
- 是吗? - 嗯.
- Yeah? - Mm-hmm.
我想重新开始. 也许要一个房子. 那会很美好.
I would like to start over again. Maybe have a house. That would be nice.
是很好. 我觉得会很棒的.
It would be great, you know. I think it'd be fabulous.
- 你也能做到的. - 是吗?
- And you could do it. - Yeah?
- 是啊. 嗯. - 现在问题是, 找一个合适的男人.
- Yeah. Mm-hmm. - The problem is, now, finding the right guy.
我要找一个爱我的人.
I need to find somebody who'll love me, you know.
一个关心我, 尊重我的人.
Somebody who'll take care of me and respect me.
我会帮你留意的.
Well, I'll keep my eye open.
也许--或者--谁知道呢?
You know, maybe-- maybe-- who knows?
唯一一点就是, Len,  他必须和我一样聪明.
The only thing is, Len, he'd have to be as smart as me.
我相信肯定有这样的人, 知道吗, 他会--
I'm sure there's somebody out there, you know, that can--
- 你会找到和你一样的. - 是吗?
- You'll find an equal somewhere. - Yeah?
不要担心, Len. 我对你放弃了.
And don't worry, Len. I gave up on you.
- 嗯-- - 我知道这不可能.
- M-- - I knew it couldn't be.
我来告诉你, 像我这样的年纪, 如果和你做爱,
Let me tell you, at my age, if I made love with you,
我必须要一个人工呼吸器.
they would have to put me on a resuscitator.
哈哈.
Ha.
- 这是Max.
-  This is Max.
- Max. - 这是我儿子.
- Max. - This is my kid.
- 你几岁了? - 5岁.
- How old are you? - I'm five.
- 你5岁了? 你想成为拳击手吗? - 对.
- You're five? You gonna be a fighter? - Yeah.
等他长大了, 他会是一个中量级选手.
Max is gonna be a middleweight when he gets older.
像你这么教导他, 他会成为一个重量级选手的.
He's gonna be a heavyweight, the way you're carryin' him.
我来教你怎么打拳, Max. 我来给你示范组合拳.
I'm gonna teach you how to box, Max. I'm gonna show you a combination punch.
1-5, 1-5. 2, 3, 4, 你要好好学.
One-five, one-five. Two, three and four, you're gonna get.
- 嘿, Ray. 这是我儿子Max. - 你好吗, Max ?
- Hey, Ray. This is my kid Max. - How you doin', Max?
Max长大后要成为中量级选手.
Max is gonna be a middleweight when he gets older.
- 也许是重量级? 对, 我觉得是重量级.
- Maybe a heavyweight? Yeah, I think a heavyweight.
- 你要和我一起去练沙袋吗? - 好的.
- You wanna go hit the bag with me? - Okay.
- 乖孩子. - 他像个玩具.
- Nice kid. - He's a doll.
嗯, Sanchez的训练怎么样了?
So, what's with the Sanchez thing?
他能赢吗? 他在训练吗? 他没有训练吗?
Is he gonna win that? ls he training? ls he not training?
- 他能赢. 他现在状态最好了. - 是吗?
- He can do it. He's in the best shape of his life. - Yeah?
唯一一点就是, 你不知道这些家伙 在体育馆外面干什么.
The only thing is, you don't know what these guys do outside the gym.
- 就是这个问题. 你听说所有的事了. - 他会没事的.
- Well, that's the point. You hear all these stories. - He'll be all right.
嘿, Kevin, 过来. 我给你介绍 我的朋友Lenny weinrib.
Hey, Kevin, come here. I wanna introduce you to my friend Lenny Weinrib.
- 他是个体育新闻记者. 他也报道拳击. - 你好吗?
- He's a sportswriter. He writes about boxing. - How you doin'?
- 听着, 我要热身, 知道吗? - 让我们看看你能做什么.
- Listen, I'm gonna get warmed up, all right? - Show us what you can do.
- 我的手仍然有点疼. - 好好包扎. 你会没事的.
- My hand's still a little sore. - Wrap it up good. You'll be okay.
- 我不认识那个孩子. - 那孩子移动很快. 出拳也不错.
- I don't know that kid. - This kid can move. He hits good too.
你知道吗, 拳速也很快?
Got nice hand speed, you know?
唯一一点就是, 你不知道这些家伙 --有时候他们缺乏渴望.
Only thing is, you don't know about these guys-- sometimes they lack desire.
我见识过无数次了.  我不知道他有没有杀手的本能.
I seen it a million times. I don't know if he's got the killer instinct.
他一直在说要回北部 回那个洋葱农场.
Keeps talkin' about goin' back upstate where he comes from on an onion farm.
- 他想成为一个洋葱农民. 你相信吗? - 那孩子是个农民?
- He wants to be an onion farmer. You believe it? - That kid's a farmer?
对, 他是个洋葱农民.  我不知道他还会逗留多久.
He's an onion farmer, yeah. I don't know how long he's gonna stick around.
就是这个问题. 也很可惜; 他打起拳来像他妈的骡子.
That's the problem. It's a shame too; he hits like a fuckin' mule.
他动作很快, 可是却想放弃拳击, 回去在农场闲逛.
He's fast, but he wants to quit boxing, go back and hang out on the farm.
退休.
You know, retire.
而且最糟糕的事, 他的女朋友离开他了.
And the worst thing of all is, his girlfriend left him.
- 她甩了他. - 真的吗?
- She quit on him. - Really?
拿走了他所有东西.
Took him for everything he's got.
他很不错, 很可爱的孩子, 可是 我只告诉你, 他脑子有点...
He's a nice, sweet kid, but between you and I, he ain't got too much upstairs.
他们都一样. 嘿, Len, 你怎么了?
They're all alike. Hey, Len, what's the matter with you?
看起来好像你脑子里在想什么.  我不明白.
Looks like you got somethin' on your mind. I don't understand.
Hey, Bo!
这-- 这是左, 这是右.
This-- This is the left, and this is the right.
- 对吗? - 对, 对, Kevin, 没错.
- Right? - Yeah, yeah, Kevin, that's right.
对.
Yeah.
[ Linda ] Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
- 嗨, Lenny. 很抱歉我要迟到了. - 没关系.
- Hi, Lenny. I'm so sorry I'm late. - It's okay.
- 下雨了. - 哦, 我没有伞.
- It's starting to rain. - Oh, I don't have an umbrella.
今天下午我认识一个男孩 我觉得对你很合适.
I met a guy this afternoon that I think would be absolutely great for you.
- 太完美了. - 我?
- Perfect. - For me?
- 是. 他很年轻, 很强壮, 很健康. - 他做什么呢?
- Yes. He's young, he's strong, he's healthy. - What does he do?
他-他-他是, 像, 在农业方面搞一些事情.
H-H-He's, you know, like, dicking around in agriculture.
他的阴茎(和搞同音)有什么问题?
What's wrong with his dick?
不, 不, 不, 他是个农民. 那个人是个农民.
No, no, no, he's a farmer. The guy's a farmer.
- 你认识农民? - 对, 一个洋葱农民. 很好.
- You met a farmer? - Yeah, an onion farmer. It's great.
- 在哪里? - 在体育馆.
- Where? - At the gym.
一个洋葱农民在体育馆里究竟能做什么?
What the hell is an onion farmer doing at the gym?
他是--他-结束了-嗯 -拳击手这个生产性的职业.
He's-- He's f-finishing a-a-a very productive career as a boxer.
拳击手? 哦, Lenny.
A boxer? Oh, Lenny.
不, 他是-- 听着, 他再也不想做一个拳击手.
No, he's-- Look, he doesn't want to be a boxer anymore.
他是-- 他想找一个合适的女孩 然后做一个农民.
H-He's-- He wants to meet the right girl and be a farmer.
- 别看我. - 他是-- 他哥哥在北部有一个很大的洋葱农场.
- Don't look at me. - He's per-- His brother has a big onion farm upstate.
考虑一下. 这会很好的.
Just think of it. It'd be so great.
一个小城镇, 你-- 你在做美容,  还有养孩子.
A small town, and you're-- y-you're hairdressing and, and raising kids.
什么小城镇?
What small town?
- wampsville. - 哪里?
- Wampsville. - Where?
wampsville. 是一个古老的印第安名字.
Wampsville. It's an old Indian name.
那-那是一个有很多美洲传统的地方.
I-I-It's a place rich in American heritage.
你他妈是不是疯了?
Are you off your fucking rocker?
要我嫁给一个洋葱农民 然后在wimpsville给人做头发?
I'm gonna go marry an onion farmer and do hair in Wimpsville?
是wampsville, 不是wimpsville.
Wampsville, not Wimpsville.
这多完美啊. 他是一个不错的人.
It's so perfect. He's a nice, sweet guy.
哦, 算了吧. 别提了.
Oh, come on. Forget it.
他很棒, 虽然. 他很聪明--你会认为他很聪明的.
He's perfect, though. He's bright-- You'll think he's bright.
- 他他妈的只不过是个洋葱农民. - 这没什么.
- He is a fucking onion farmer. - That's okay.
他是个不错的孩子. 更重要的是, 他很老实正派.
He's a nice kid. More important, he's honest and decent.
还有记住不要在见面刚5分钟 就提出给他口交,
And don't offer to give him a blow job in the first five minutes,
- '因为他想, 你是个美容师. - 你撒谎了?
- 'cause he thinks you're a hairdresser. - You lied?
- 我-- - 你不应该撒谎.
- I-- - You shouldn't lie.
就按我说的去做. 只要听我这一次.
Just do what I'm telling you. Just listen to me for once.
我和所有女孩都结束了, Lenny.
I'm off the girls, Lenny.
我的意思是, 和我一起的最后一个女孩 骗走了我所有的钱, 伙计.
I mean, the last girl I was with cheated me out of all my dough, man.
我跟你说, 那是个很好的女孩, Kevin. 她很不错.
I'm telling you, this is a nice kid, Kevin. She's nice.
-你是说那个美容师? -就是那个美容师.
-This the hairdresser you told me about? -This is the hairdresser.
我给你制造了很好的机会. 要知道那个女孩可以挑她喜欢的任何男人.
I gave you a big buildup. This girl could have her pick of any guy she wants.
- 我帮你说了很多好话. - 你和她说了什么?
- I said good things about you. - What'd you tell her?
我告诉她你很英俊, 是个帅小伙;
I told her you were handsome, a good-looking guy;
你是个很好的运动员; 你很有天分, 很聪明.
that you're a great athlete; that you're gifted, bright.
- 你没有撒谎. - 我会撒谎吗? 当然不会.
- You didn't lie. - Would I lie? Of course not.
你和她说了我很能打吗?
You told her I could fight?
我和她说了, 但是打动她的...
I told her, but what touches her heart...
是你想成为一个农民.
is that you want to be a farmer.
这是个喜欢土壤的女孩, 我想你保证.
This is a girl that has a love of the soil, I promise you.
洋葱. 是洋葱. 我哥哥有个洋葱农场.
Onions. Onions. My brother's got an onion farm.
我想回到那里,  因为我想离开这该死的城市.
I wanna go back up there 'cause I wanna get the hell outta this city.
太棒了! 你和Linda提到洋葱,  她就会发狂!
That's perfect! You mention onions to Linda, she goes crazy!
你说''洋葱'', 她会发狂
She goes nuts, you say "onion."
你对Linda说''洋葱'', 她就会--
You say "onion" to Linda, the girl is just--
好了, 好了,  好了, 好了, 好了.
All right, all right, all right, all right, all right.
那是她的名字? Linda?
That's her name? Linda?
Linda. 很好听的名字. 你怎么这儿, 这儿, 这么冷淡--
Linda. It's a pretty name. What are you so, so, so standoffish--
- 是有''E-R''还是''U-R''的那个? - 什么有''E-R''还是--
- Is that with an "E-R" or a "U-R"? - Is what with an "E-R" or--
- ''Linder'' ? - Linda. 有''A''的那个Linda. Linda.
- "Linder"? - Linda. Linda with an "A." Linda.
- 哦. - 她是个很棒的女孩.
- Oh. - She's a great kid.
她还是个很实在的女人.
And she's a substantial woman.
她不是傻乎乎的女孩.
This is not a dumb girl.
她有-有-有...茎和小囊文化的博士学位.
This girl has got a PhD i-i-in... root and follicle culture.
- 她很漂亮, 是吗? - 漂亮极了. 她美极了.
- And she's pretty, right? - To die. She's to die.
因为这个很重要. 因为我被伤害过.
'Cause that's important. 'Cause I've been stung.
和我在一起的最后一个女孩 炸干了我所有东西, 伙计.
The last girl I was with drove me up the wall, man.
- 她让我觉得恶心. - Linda是一个教徒.
- She made my stomach sick to the stomach. - Linda is church people.
- 我就要这样的. 我要一个教徒女孩. - 她很棒.
- That's what I want. I want a church girl. - She's great.
我想要一个不错的教徒女孩;  我不想要那些放荡的纽约荡妇.
I want a nice church girl; I don't want one of these fast New York sluts.
我想要一个不错的, 顾家的女孩 她喜欢照顾家庭, 养狗之类的.
I want a nice, homely girl who likes to raise a family and dogs and that kind of thing.
我可以对你说几个字吗? 我可以说几个字吗?
Can I say two words to you? Can I say two words?
太巧了. 知道吗?
Butter churn. Okay?
太巧了. 这是个先锋派女孩.
Butter churn. This is a pioneer girl.
这个女孩, 顺便说一下, 几乎是个处女.
This is a girl who is practically, incidentally, a virgin.
你说''几乎''是什么意思?
What do you mean, "practically"?
我想对你说实话-- 她-她只和一两个男人睡过.
I wanna level with you-- sh-she's slept with one or two guys in her life.
一个大学老教授...
An old college professor...
和-和-一个初恋情人.
a-a-and her childhood sweetheart.
不过他们两个都在为他们国家的战斗中被杀了.
But both of them were killed in combat for their nation.
- 这是个伤心的故事. - 一个教授在战斗中被杀了?
- It's a sad story. - A professor got killed in combat?
人文团体.
Humanities regiment.
你知道吗, 他们是最先到达Anzio的那些人.  我告诉你--
You know, they were the first ones to land at Anzio. I'm telling you--
你说她是个演员? 她演过一些电影?
You said she was an actress? She's been in some films?
-她演过一些很棒的角色, 对. -她有没有演过我看过的什么电影?
-She's had a couple of good roles, yeah. -She's ever been in anything I seen?
嘿-- 你没看过辛德勒的名单吗?
Hey-- You didn't see Schindler's List?
没有, 没有-- 那-那是-- 那是讲犹太人的, 嗯--
No, no, no-- T-That was-- That was-- That was the one with the Jews and, um--
- 那些坏人是谁来着? - 那些金发的家伙是纳粹.
- Who were the bad guys? - The blond guys were the Nazis.
- 他们都是残暴的混蛋. - 对, 就是.
- They were tough motherfuckers. - Yeah, all right.
我告诉你, 这是个好女孩. 她好极了.
I'm telling you, this is a good girl. She's wonderful.
他在扮演上帝.
He's playing God.
如果他可以成功 这也很不错.
It would be nice if he could bring this off.
这是自以为是!
It's hubris!
他花了这么多时间为她准备.
He spent a lot of time preparing her.
听着, 你有没有, 嗯--
Listen, have you, uh--
在考虑过我们谈论的问题?
given any more thought to what we discussed?
是. 是, 我有.
Yeah. Yeah, I did.
我的意思是-- 你看, 问题是, 我不知道 是什么感觉; 我很困惑.
I mean-- Look, the problem is, I don't know how I feel anymore; I'm confused.
- 我-- - 听着, Amanda, 我爱你.
- I-- - Listen, Amanda, I love you.
是吗?
Yeah?
如果你不给自己一个机会 你永远都不会原谅你自己的.
You're never gonna be able to forgive yourself if you don't give it a try.
Kevin.
这是Linda. Linda, 这是, 嗯--
This is Linda. Linda, this is, uh--
这是Kevin.
This is Kevin.
- 你好吗? - 嗨.
- How you doin'? - Hi.
嗯--
So--
我要走了-- 我只是把你们带到一起.
I'll go and-- I just wanted to bring you guys together, you know.
也许, 你可以留下来.
You know, you could maybe stick around, maybe.
我们可以出去什么的.
You know, we could go out or somethin'.
- 对啊. - 不, 不. 我完全是多余的.
- Yeah. - No, no. I'm completely superfluous.
哦, 你不舒服?
Oh, you don't feel good?
不, 我是多余的. 我真的是多余的.
No, I'm superfluous. I'm completely unnecessary.
你们可以玩得开心点 我要-- 我还有事要做.
You guys can have a great time and I'll-- I got stuff to do, you know.
- 这是给你的. - 这是什么, 菊花吗?
- I got these for you. - What are these, daisies?
- 嗯-- - 很不错.
- Uh-- - That's great.
这很好.
That's nice.
对-- 对.
Yeah-- Ye-- Yeah.
我想你说过他是个农民.
I thought you said that he was a farmer.
嗯, 他是-- 他是农民.
Well, he is-- He's a farmer.
- 我知道这不是洋葱. - 菊花会让我打喷嚏的, Lenny.
- I know they're not onions. - Daisies make me sneeze, Lenny.
过来一下. 不好意思.
Come here a minute. Excuse us one second.
这些花很美. 告诉他这些花很美 然后过得开心点.
They're beautiful flowers. Tell him they're beautiful and enjoy yourself.
- 我可以拿着这些花. - 我知道, 可是他们会让我打喷嚏的.
- I could hold the flowers. - I know, but they just make me sneeze.
- 她对花过敏. 如果你打喷嚏这是个好兆头. - 我拿着这些花.
- She sneezes with flowers. That's good luck if you sneeze. - I'll hold the flowers.
- 谢谢. - 走吧, 开心点. 我们回头见.
- Thanks. - Go ahead, have fun. I'll see you guys.
我要走了.
I'm gonna go.
小心点.
Take care.
嗯, 你-- 你很漂亮.
So, y-- you're pretty.
嗯-- 他... 他说的是实话.
Uh-- He's... tellin' the truth.
- 你真的... - 哦.
- You're really... - Oh.
很美.
pretty.
- 谢谢. 你也不错啊. - 对, 我知道.
- Thanks. You're not so bad yourself. - Yeah, I know.
我打赌你愣得像匹马.
I bet you're hung like a horse.
- 对, 我会骑马. - 是吗?
- Yeah, I can ride a horse. - Yeah?
你知道吗, 我哥哥有个农场, 我喜欢动物.
You know, my brother's got a farm, you know. I love animals.
我喜欢动物. 他在北部农场里养 鸭子啊, 猪啊什么的, 嗯--
I like animals. He's got a farm up there with the ducks and the pigs and, um--
哦, 对. 在wisconsin.
Oh, yeah. In Wisconsin.
是wampsville.
Wampsville.
- 那, 我们去动物园, 啊? - ''你?''
- ''对我?'' - 好的.
- ''做了什么?'' - ''Doo doo-doo-doo''
''什么''
''如此简单地诱惑''
''诱惑了我''
- ''告诉我'' - ''你是否愿意告诉我''
- ''我'' - ''来吧告诉我''
''为什么会这样''
''你有''
''能力让我''
''着迷''
''让''
- ''我'' - ''让我''
''生活在你的符咒下''
''你这么精通''
''用巫术迷惑''
- ''因为你'' - ''Doo doo-doo-doo''
- ''对我'' - ''Doo doo-doo-doo''
''做了什么''
''没有其他任何人''
''能够做到''
''你做到了, 哦''
- 我打过16场比赛, 赢了12场. - ''没有人''
- 哦, 很有印象. - ''其他任何人''
对. 你做头发多久了?
Yeah. How long were you doin' hair?
- ''可以做到'' - 嗯, 我现在才刚刚开始.
- 哦, 对, 因为你原来在演戏, 对吗? - 对.
- That's right, 'cause you were doin' the acting, right? - Yeah.
- 对啊. 我没有看过辛德勒的名单. - 我也没有.
- That's right. I didn't get to see Schindler's List. - Me neither.
不过你还演过什么其他电影呢?
But what were some of the other films you were in?
嗯, 我演了''诱人的...'', 嗯--
Well, I did The Enchanted, uh--
- ''沙拉''. - ''诱人的沙拉''?
- Salad. - The Enchanted Salad?
有关什么的? 好看吗?
What was that about? Is it good?
是啊, 很好看. 是有关一个女服务生的.
Yeah, it was really good. It was about a waitress.
是嘛.
Yeah.
- 我今晚和你一起很开心. - 是吗?
- I had a really good time with you tonight. - Did you?
- 是的. - 真的吗? 我也是.
- Yeah. - Really? Me too.
对, 你投币机游戏玩得很好.
Yeah, you're really good at arcade games, you know.
因为我以前和一个 玩弹球的男人约会过.
Well, I used to date a pinball champ, not for nothing.
弹球男-- 那是, 嗯 很认真的关系吗?
Pinball ch-- Was it, like, a serious relationship?
嗯, 我们订婚了, 不过两个人扼死了他.
Well, we were getting engaged, but then two guys strangled him.
哦.
Oh.
- 你知道我喜欢什么样的女人吗? - 什么?
- You know what I like in a woman? - What?
我喜欢, 就像, 嗯, 传统的女孩,
I like, like, um, an old-fashioned girl, you know,
就像我妈妈.
Iike my-my mom.
就像, 喜欢照顾家里 喜欢做饭打扫的女孩...
Like, a girl who likes to take care of the house and cook and clean...
不介意去遛狗, 整理草坪之类的.
and doesn't mind walkin' the dogs and doin' the lawn and that kind of thing.
你明白我的意思吗? 就像我妈妈一样的女孩.
You know what I mean? That's like my mom.
对.
Yeah.
你喜欢什么样的男人?
What do you like in a man?
我喜欢他有一个好工作,
I like a guy who has a good job,
对我很好 还有, 嗯--
who treats me nice and, um--
嗯, 有几分像你这样.
Well, who's kinda built like you.
不需要把袜子塞进内裤来显得好看一些.
Doesn't have to stuff a sock in his jock to look good.
嗯.
Mm-hmm.
- 你知道我有什么梦想吗? - 什么?
- You know what my dream is? - What?
我在一片田野里, 知道吗?
I'm in a field, right?
然后, 就像, 那只鹰飞来...
And, like, this hawk comes...
用它的嘴把我叼起来,
and picks me up in his beak, right?
然后带着我飞, 环绕全世界 这样我就能看见所有的东西.
And then flies me, like, all over the world so I see everything.
然后, 它带我飞出这个国家...
And then, like, he flies me out of the country...
然后, 我们飞到北极 它把我扔在那里...
and, like, we go up to the north pole and he drops me...
在雪地里.
in the snow.
然后我只是躺在那里...
And I'm just layin' there...
赤裸裸的.
naked.
你有什么梦想?
What's your dream?
我的梦想是由个人和我一起 觉得我是特别的一个,
My dream is that somebody would come along and think that I was special,
然后-- 然后他愿意来 为我改变我的生活.
that, you know-- that they'd wanna come and change my life for me.
这是我的梦想.
That's my dream.
你会实现的.
You could have that.
- 你这样觉得吗? - 对, 我觉得.
- You think? - Yeah, I think.
像你这么漂亮的女孩, 你肯定可以实现的.
You could definitely have that, a pretty girl like you.
这么说, 你觉得, 嗯,
So, you think, um,
我会再来看你, 还是什么?
I'm gonna get to see you again, Linda, or what?
你想吗?
Do you want to?
非常想.
A lot.
我非常想.
I want to a lot.
我也是.
Me too.
真爱. 像泉水一样凉爽.
True love. As refreshing as spring.
他们吻别, 互道晚安.
They kissed good night.
第二个晚上, 第三个晚上又见面了.
And saw each other the very next night, and the next.
等一下. 有人进来了.
Hold it, everybody. Something's coming in.
- 一个公告! - 哦. 令人扫兴的人来了.
- A bulletin! - Uh-oh. Here comes Miss Party Pooper.
Tiresias, 失明的底比斯预言家.
Tiresias, the blind seer of Thebes.
- 我看到他和weinrib在一起的画面. - 在哪里?
- I have a vision of him and Weinrib. -  Where?
等等.
Wait.
The Acropolis.
哦, weinrib.
Oh, Weinrib.
我看到你太太了.
I saw your wife.
- Amanda. - 你认识我吗?
- Amanda.  - You know me?
对. 我看到她了. 她在画廊工作到很晚.
Yeah. I saw her. She was workin' late at the gallery.
她和, 嗯, 一个叫Jerry Bender的家伙一起.
And with her was this, uh, Jerry Bender guy.
哦, 这没什么. 她和Jerry Bender 一起工作. 没什么奇怪的.
Well, that's nothing. She works with Jerry Bender. Nothing unusual.
- 你还没让我说完呢. - 继续吧.
- You didn't let me finish. - Go on.
嗯, 他们用亲密的语气交谈...
Uh, they spoke in intimate tones...
然后, 嗯, Bender给了她 深深的湿湿的...
and then, uh, Bender rose and laid a big wet one on her.
- 深深的湿湿的-- Bender亲了Amanda ? - 这就是我要告诉你的.
- A big we-- Bender kissed Amanda? - That's what I'm tellin' ya.
嘿, 你一定知道有些事 发生有一段时间了, 啊?
Hey, you must've known somethin' was going on for a while, huh?
是, 我总是认为Bender只是 用眼睛占她便宜.
Yeah, I always thought that Bender had eyes for her.
现在连手都用上了.
Now he's got eyes and hands.
妈的-- 那, Amanda 没有回应, 是吗?
Jesus-- Well, Amanda didn't respond, did she?
不. 她把嘴巴张开了, 伸出了舌头...
No. She just opened her mouth very wide and stuck her tongue out...
尽力地伸长.
as far as it was humanly possible to go.
妈的-- 你确定吗?
Jeez-- Are you sure?
嘿-- 特洛伊木马会有木头阴茎吗?
Well, hey-- Does the Trojan horse have a wooden dick?
- 然后, 她把腰部靠着他. - 好了, 好了!
- And then she, she pushed her abdomen against his. - All right, all right!
我能想象到! 我知道了! 我就怀疑.
I got the picture! I knew it! I always suspected.
啊, 这是你不想知道的, 你就当作什么也没看见吧.
Ah, it's somethin' you don't wanna know, but you hadda be blind not to see it.
- 哦, 上帝. 我要面对她. - 哦, 不, 不要在Max面前!
- Yeah. Oh, God. I'm gonna confront her. - Oh, no, not in front of Max!
不, Max-- Max会在他朋友家里过一个晚上.
No, Max-- Max has got a sleep-over date at his friend's house.
- 哦. - 不. 我知道. 我早就明白了.
- Oh. - No. I knew it. Down deep, I knew it.
嗯, 谢谢, weinrib. 谢谢.
Uh, thanks, Weinrib. Thanks.
啊, 谢谢. 上帝保佑你.
Ah, thank you. God bless you.
哦, 天哪! 这比我们想象的严重得多!
Oh, my God! It's more serious than we thought!
太严重了. 她和Lenny的婚姻出现危机了.
It's very serious. Her marriage to Lenny is in crisis.
随着时间的流逝, 即使最稳固的关系也会变脆弱.
With the passage of time, even the strongest bonds become fragile.
好极了, 伙计们. 听起来就像幸运饼.
Great, fellas. It sounds like a fortune cookie.
哦 宙斯, 最强大的神啊!
O Zeus, most potent of gods!
我们恳求你! 我们需要你的帮助!
We implore thee! We need your help!
宙斯! 伟大的宙斯! 听见了吗! 听见了吗!
Zeus! Great Zeus! Hear us! Hear us!
我们呼唤你!
We call out to thee!
嗯, 我是宙斯. 我现在不在家.
Um, this is Zeus. I'm not home right now.
不过你可以留个口信 我会找你的.
But you can leave a message and I'll get back to you.
- 请在''哔''的一声后开始留言.
- Please start speaking at the tone.
回来给我们打电话! 我们需要帮助!
Call us when you get in! We need help!
上帝, 我觉得我应该搬出去.
God, I think I should move out.
我-我-我不明白. 这-- 这太突然了.
I-I-I can't understand this. Wh-Wh-- This is so radical.
不, 因为我不能欺骗你. Jerry Bender爱上我了.
No, 'cause I can't cheat. Jerry Bender's in love with me.
这太疯狂了.
This is crazy.
你是说你爱他吗, 你爱Jerry Bender吗?
Are you telling me you're in love with him, you're in love with Jerry Bender?
我不知道. 我想弄清楚.
I don't know. I gotta find out.
- 你什么意思, ''你不知道'' ? - 我不知道!
- What do you mean, "you don't know"? - I don't know!
你到底什么意思? 你到底爱不爱他?
What do you mean? Are you in love with him or not?
不管怎么样, Lenny, 让我们面对现实-- 我们之间已经变了.
Anyway, Lenny, let's face it-- things have changed between us.
可是我们可以弥补. Max怎么办? Max--
But we can fix things. What about Max? Max--
他会没事的. 也许我们分开对他会更好...
He'll be okay. Maybe it will be better for him with us apart...
- 不用这样在一起不停吵架. - 这太疯狂了.
- instead of together and arguing all of the time. - That's crazy.
我觉得这太疯狂了.
I just think that's crazy.
我-- 我没办法谈下去.
Well, I-- I can't have this conversation.
我-- 这太疯狂了. 我--
I-- This is too crazy. I'm--
- 你要去哪里? - 我要出去. 我要想想.
- Where are you going? - I'm going out. I have to think.
我要好好想清楚.
I have to get my thoughts together.
- 我等你很久了, 伙计. - Kevin, 别烦我.
- I been waitin' for you, man. - Kevin, leave me alone.
- 我心情很不好. - 你心情不好?
- I'm in a very, very bad mood. - You're in a very bad mood?
你怎么可以这么做? 你怎么可以把我 和那个笨女孩弄到一起?
How could you do this? How could you set me up with this stupid girl?
- 你在说什么? - 你没告诉我她是个妓女...
- What are you talking about? - You didn't tell me she was a hooker...
还有她演的是色情片 她和几百个男人上过床...
and that she did porno films and had sex with hundreds and hundreds of men...
还有女人, 妈的谁知道还有什么!
and women and who the hell knows what else!
- 我觉得你有偏见. - 什么?
- I thought it would prejudice you. - What?
你怎么知道的?
How did you find out?
我-我给我朋友打电话, 告诉他们 我找到一个女朋友我想结婚.
I-l call my friends up and I tell 'em I got this girl that I wanna marry.
他们让我过去喝了点酒 我的朋友Ray打开色情录像.
They have me over for a few drinks and my friend Ray puts in this sexy video.
你知道, 我对色情东西不是很感兴趣.
But I'm not really into pornography, you know.
- 我看了一眼屏幕, 女演员居然是Judy Cum.
- I look on the screen and this actress is up there: Judy Cum.
Kevin, 我告诉过你她喜欢演戏.
Kevin, I told you she had dramatic aspirations.
- 我没办法接受. - 哦, 妈的. 我还以为你很开明呢.
- I flew off the handle. - Oh, Christ. I thought you were a broad-minded guy.
我来这儿, 她承认了这一切 然后我-- 我打了她.
I came over here and she confessed to everything, and then I-- and I hit her.
- 你打了她? 你打-- - 我会打断你的脖子, 伙计!
- You hit her? You hi-- - I was gonna break your neck, man!
- 我都不敢相信. 你打了她? - 我不相信!
- I don't believe this. You hit her? - I don't believe this!
- 你打了她? 为了他妈的-- - 一点点.
- You hit her? For Christ's-- - A little bit.
- 上帝. - 我打电话给我妈妈. 我很难过, 她说我应该回家去.
- God. - I called my mother. I was upset, so then she says I should come home.
- 所以我要离开这该死的鬼地方. - 我不明白你.
- So I'm gonna get the hell outta this place, man. - I don't understand you.
你是个开明的人. 人都会改变.  你就因为她的过去而放弃她?
You're a broad-minded guy. People change. You gonna hold her past against her?
- 对, 我要-- 色情明星! - 你爱她, 她也爱你!
- Yeah, I'm gonna--  A porno star! - You love her, she loves you!
- 你在说什么呢? - 算了吧, 伙计. 就这样了.
- What are you talking about? - Forget it, man. It's over.
从第一天开始我就和你说过 她不是处女.
I told you from day one the girl was not a virgin.
可是你没有说她有过多少次!
You didn't tell me how many times though!
- 谢谢你什么都没帮上, Lenny, 伙计. - Kevin!
- Thanks for nothin', Lenny, man. - Kevin!
不, 伙计!
Nah, man!
- 他打了我.
- He hit me.
我知道, 我-- 我在楼下碰到他--
I know, I-- I ran into him downstairs and he--
哦, 天哪, 你看你.
Oh, Jesus, look at you.
上帝, 很疼吗?
God, does it feel terrible?
不, 不是很疼. 只是我的溃疡.
No, not really. Just my ulcer.
溃疡? 哦, 你不应该喝酒.
Your ulcer? Well, you know, you shouldn't be drinking.
- 嗯. - 这糟透了-- 哦, 上帝, 你看你.
- Hmm. - That's the worst-- Oh, God, look at that.
Boy.
- 还记得你说过我们都是失败者? - 是啊.
- Remember you once said we were a couple of losers? - Yeah.
嗯, 我觉得太对了.
Well, I think that's definitely true.
- 为什么? 你发生什么事了?
- Why? What happened to you?
Amanda离开我了.
Amanda left me.
哦. 我很抱歉, Lenny.
Oh. I'm sorry, Lenny.
你要喝一杯吗?
Would you like a drink?
嗯. 不.
Mmm. No.
什么, 嗯-- 怎么了?
What's, uh-- What's-- What's the matter?
我-- 我不知道.
I-- I don't know.
她很好吗? 你可以跟我说.
Was she great? You can tell me.
她-- 她在床上很棒吗?
Was she-- Was she great in bed?
- 经验丰富的女人. - 我不知道.
- A woman with all that experience. - I don't know.
我只知道忽然我很想Amanda.
I just know that suddenly I really miss Amanda.
等等! 看谁来了!
But wait! See who approaches!
你在这儿! 你去哪里了?
There you are! Where have you been?
我一直在到处找你.
I've been looking for you all over.
我只是出去喝了点东西 想想所有这些事.
I was just out drinking and thinking about everything.
哦, Lenny, 对不起.
Oh, Lenny, I'm sorry.
我, 嗯-- 我整夜都没睡 都在想我伤害了你...
I, uh-- I was up all night thinking how much I hurt you...
还有我把我们都弄得多糟,
and how much I'd messed us up for good,
还有不能和你在一起.
and the thought of not being with you.
我爱你. 我根本不爱Jerry.
I love you. I don't love Jerry at all.
不管要做什么, 我们应该让一切恢复正常.
We have to put things right, whatever has to be done.
''当你寂寞的时候''
''魔力的月光也消逝''
''在黎明前''
''不会有日出''
- ''当你的爱人离开的时候'' - 至于Linda,
她到北部的wampsville去 去求Kevin重归于好...
she drove upstate to Wampsville and pleaded with Kevin to take her back...
可是没有用.
but to no avail.
在回家的路上她都抓狂了 感觉生命没有希望了...
Anyway, on the way home she was distraught and felt life held no hope...
这时-- 解围的人出现了--
when-- talk about a deus ex machina--
''像凋谢的花''
''生命不代表一切''
''当你的爱人离开你的时候''
我们的退火装置有点问题 那东西有点失去平衡.
So we just had a stabilizing problem and the thing got a little off balance.
然后无线电通信失灵, 所以我要降落找个电话.
And then the radio went glitchy, so I just need to get down and use a phone.
不管怎么样,  非常谢谢你, 停下来帮我.
And thank you very much, by the way, for stopping.
我叫Don.
My name's Don.
然后Linda结婚了.
And so Linda married.
嫁给了一个开明的接受她的男人...
To a wonderful man who was not uptight and repressed and accepted her...
他甚至拿她复杂的背景故事开玩笑.
and even laughed at wild tales of her promiscuous background.
这样我们小小的希腊戏剧就--
And so our little Greek drama comes to--
等等, 等等. 还有呢.
Wait, wait, wait. There's more.
还有什么, Tiresias, 失明的底比斯预言家?
What more, Tiresias, blind seer of Thebes?
告诉他们只要叫我Tiresias, 可以吗?
Tell 'em just to call me Tiresias, will ya?
残疾人总是有怪癖.
The handicapped are always cranky.
在那个晚上, Lenny weinrib和Linda做爱了,
On that night, Lenny Weinrib and Linda did make love,
就像他是宙斯, 而她是阿芙罗迪蒂.
Iike he was Zeus and she was Aphrodite with an aphrodisiac.
说重点!
Get to the point!
- 重点是, Linda在那个晚上就怀孕了. - 不!
- The point is, Linda did, that night, conceive a child. - No!
是的. 她有了Lenny的孩子.
Yes. She became pregnant with Lenny's child.
但是她不想破坏他和Amanda的生活,  她从来没有告诉他.
But not wanting to complicate his life with Amanda, she never told him.
她和她新丈夫一起离开了,
Instead she went off with her new husband,
在她生下那个漂亮的女婴时 她丈夫始终忠心地对她.
who stood behind her loyally as she gave birth to a beautiful baby girl.
Lenny再也没有见过Linda.
Lenny never saw Linda again.
- 然后在纽约一个秋天的日子. - ''时钟滴滴答答''
''孩子们在玩耍''
- ''让愉快的笑声赶走我们的烦恼'' - 他们可能在后面.
如果你愿意, 我们可以逛完整个商店.
We can look around the whole store if you'd like.
''欢迎来到玩具世界''
- Lenny ! - 我简直不敢相信! 嗯--
- Lenny! - I don't believe this! Wh--
- 嗨. - 你在这里干嘛?
-  Hi. - What are you doing here?
- 我-我-- - 我没看错吧! 你发生什么了?
- I-I-- - I'm stunned! What happened to you?
我-我住在康涅狄格.
I-I'm living in Connecticut.
我结婚了, 我丈夫Don是个直升机飞行员.
I'm married and my husband Don is a helicopter pilot.
你在开玩笑! 你去哪里了? 我到处找你.
You're kidding! Where did you go? I searched every place for you.
- 就好像你从这个地球的表面消失了似的. - 我们曾经在一起过.
- It's like you vanished off the face of the earth. - Well, we had our moment.
- 可是我知道你会回到Amanda身边. - 我不相信-- 这太好了.
- But I knew you would be back with Amanda. - I can't b-- That's super.
- 那-那你结婚了--这个是你的孩子? - 对! 你看她.
- S-So y-you're married and-- This is yours? - Yes! Look at her.
哦, 上帝, 她好可爱啊.
Oh, God, she's adorable.
- 她太可爱了. 非常--
- She's adorable. Very, very--
- 那他-- 是Max ? - 他就是Max.
- And is-- Is that Max? - This is Max. This is Max.
- 你好. - Max, 问好. 这是我朋友.
- Hello. - Max, say hello. This is a friend.
- 嗨, 我是Linda. - 你好吗?
- Hi, I'm Linda. - How do you do?
好帅的小男孩. Amanda一定很漂亮.
What a handsome boy. Amanda must be very beautiful.
她-- 你也一定有个英俊的丈夫,
And she's-- You've gotta have a very handsome husband,
因为她长得很漂亮.
'cause she has a great face.
我都晕了. 我不知道该说什么. 我, 我--
I'm stunned. I don't know what to say. I'm, I'm--
- Lenny, 能见到你太好了. - 你也是. 你还好吗? 一切--
- Lenny, it's so great to see you. - You too. You're okay? Everything--
对. 我很好.
Yeah. I'm really good.
谢谢你所做的一切.
Thank you for everything.
哦-- 我-我-- 我说不出话了.
Oh-- I-I-- I'm speechless.
我-我-- 我要走了. 不好意思. 我要迟到了.
I-I-- I gotta go. I'm sorry. I'm gonna be late.
- 很高兴见到你. - 很高兴见到你. 太好了.
- It was great to see you. - It was great to see you. Great.
- 可是他们有彼此的孩子.
- But they have each other's child.
而他们又不知道.
And they don't know.
是啊. 是啊. 生活就是这么讽刺?
Yes. Yes. Isn't life ironic?
生活就是难以置信啊.
Life is unbelievable.
不可思议. 悲哀. 奇妙.
Miraculous. Sad. Wonderful.
是啊, 说的都对!
Yes, this is all true!
所以我们说:
And that's why we say:
- ''当你微笑的时候'' - ''Doo-doo-doo-doo, doo-doo''
''当你微笑的时候''
''Doo-doo-doo-doo Doo-doo, doo-doo''
- ''整个世界'' - ''Doo-doo-doo-doo, doo-doo''
''和你一起微笑''
''Ooh, 保持微笑''
- ''当你笑的时候'' - ''Doo-doo-doo-doo, doo-doo''
- ''当你笑的时候'' - ''Doo doo-doo, doo-doo, doo-doo''
''阳光保持灿烂''
''Ooh ooh''
- ''可是当你哭泣的时候'' - ''Ooh ooh-ooh-ooh''
''天空开始下雨''
- ''所以不要叹息'' - ''Ooh ooh-ooh-ooh''
''重新恢复快乐''
''保持微笑''
''因为当你微笑的时候''
''整个世界''
''和你一起微笑''
''当你微笑的时候''
''整个世界''
''和你一起微笑''
''当你笑的时候''
''阳光保持''
''灿烂''
''可是当你哭泣的时候''
''天空开始下雨''
''所以停止叹息''
''重新恢复快乐''
''保持微笑''
''因为当你微笑的时候''
''整个世界''
''和你一起微笑''
“非强力春药”  -=结束=-